翻译、校对： 韩非XF
请勿用于商业用途，尊重他人劳动成果
在意大利，要定义一种东西为毒品
In Italy to be defined as a drug
就必须列在卫生部非法制剂的清单上
a substance has to be on the Ministry of Health's illegal molecules list.
比如可卡因、海洛因、冰毒、美沙酮、摇头丸等
Cocaine, heroin, amphetamines, methadone, ecstasy,
清单里还列出了约200种其它制剂
and more or less 200 other molecules make up that list.
假如一种制剂不在清单上
If a molecule isn't on that list,
那么你就可以制造和服用它。不过，最重要的是，你可以出售它
then you can make it, take it, but, above all, you can sell it.
我在24岁那年以最高成绩从生物专业毕业
I graduated in biology at the age of 24 with top marks,
我拥有计算神经学的硕士学位
I have a master's in computational neuroscience
以及分子动力学学位
and another in molecular dynamics.
最近几个月我成立了一个帮派
In the last few months I've set up a gang
从事一项价值数十万欧元的买卖
that runs a business worth hundreds of thousands of euros
我被指控生产和贩卖毒品、武装抢劫
I've been accused of producing and pushing drugs, armed robbery,
绑架以及蓄意杀人
kidnap and attempted homicide.
我叫彼得罗·兹尼，是一名大学研究员
My name is Pietro Zinni, and I'm a university researcher.
玩命毒师
I CAN QUIT ANYTIME I WANT
四个月前
4 MONTHS BEFORE
...根据现有分子对接软件的特定参照
...with particular reference to current molecular docking software,
一般基于长期的，按我们的观点来说
often based on long and, in our opinion,
不可靠的卡查尔斯基·卡泽尔算法推演过程
unreliable phases of elaboration of the Katchalski-Katzir algorithm.
而我们的目的是为了获取一个更直接
Our aim instead is to obtain a result that is much more immediate
更精确的结果。这就是为什么我们要向
and much more precise. And that is why we are asking
- 这个委员会申请资金...   - 抱歉，是我的
- this commission to finance...   - Sorry, that's mine.
...以进行深入研究
...further research.
抱歉，是我的手机响
Given the very delicate moment, I have to keep it on.
安吉洛，兄弟...
Angelo, my man...
好的
Yes.
这些我已获得塞塔·兹尼命名的改良
These upgrades which I have taken the liberty of naming Seta-Zinni,
已经得出一些惊人的结果
have led to some surprising results.
我们发现了，比方说，TAAR1型酶
We discovered, for example, how the TAAR1 enzyme,
是怎样进入单胺的膜泡运输机制
entering the vesicular transport mechanism of the monoamines,
这可以得到，像这一页所示，令人难以置信的结果
is able to achieve, as you can see in this slide here, incredible results.
- 从这个角度来说...   - 该死的！
- From the point of view of...   - Damnation !
- 肯定是有...   - 肯定哪有问题！
- There must be...   - Something's wrong !
还有什么东西烧着了的味道！
There's a smell of burning as well !
什么东西都不符合标准，整栋楼都不可靠
Nothing here is legal, the whole building is barely safe.
- 彼得罗，长话短说吧...   - 不，它停掉了...
- Pietro, a little flexibility...   - No, it's stuck...
后面看看论文就行了
Finish up with the paper version,
我相信教授们已经抓住了这项研究的重点
I'm sure the professors have grasped the importance of the research.
我去找一个试验室技术员
I'll go and get a lab technician.
- 弗朗西斯科！   - 我把论文给你们
- Francesco !   - I'll give out the paper version.
哦，老天，抱歉
Oh, God, excuse me.
教授，很抱歉，投影仪出问题了
Professor, I'm sorry, but the problem with the projector,
在某些方面我们要更仔细一些！
we need to be more careful with certain things !
彼得罗，这很严重
Pietro, this is serious,
这次掉电把事情都搞砸了
this brownout has messed up everything,
我连我的地址薄都进不去了
I can't even access my address book.
恕我直言，教授，我们现在讨论的事有关职业生涯！
With all due respect, Professor, We're talking about career here !
如果我的研究得不到新的资金，我就失业了
If they don't refinance my research, I'm out of a job.
什么？我们进行得不错！
What ? We're doing fine !
现在我们需要寻求政策性保护，我早已着手在办了
Now we need to find some political protection, and I've already dealt with that.
我一点都不明白这些政治手段...
I don't understand this political thing at all...
左手第二位是华盛顿的德·米塔的秘书
The second from the left was secretary to De Mita in the DC,
我是在1986年阿韦利诺举办的君主主义大会上认识他的
and I met him '86 at a monarchists' convention in Avellino.
- 我跟他说你是我们的人   - 什么我们？
- I said you were one of ours.   - Our what ?
- 共融与自由团体   - 是吗，我不是太...
- Communion and Liberation.   - Really, I'm not exactly...
这他妈有什么关系，彼得罗？关键是他笑了
And why the fuck should that matter Pietro ? What matters is that he smiled.
你知道那意味着什么吗？一份长期合同
You know what that means ? A long-term contract.
但愿如此！我希望资金能够比较稳定
I wish ! I could really use some financial stability.
没错，不过，考虑一下，我们能不能试试重启下手机？
Yes, but, as a scruple, shall we try and reset the device ?
教授，我很忙，明天再试吧
Professor, I'm in a rush, I'll do it tomorrow.
我就这样守着用不起来的手机过一下午？
And I would have to spend all afternoon with my cell phone not working ?
你确实要走的话，走吧
If you have to go, go.
我会找你的同事贾科梅蒂让他试试
I'll ask your colleague Giacometti and he'll do it.
这关贾科梅蒂什么事？让我来吧
What's Giacometti got to do with it ? I'll do it.
你去哪了？快4点了！
Where have you been ? It's nearly 4 !
我跟教授碰上点事情...
I had a problem with the professor...
看看，彼得罗！情况真要命
Look at this, Pietro ! The situation's tragic.
- 孩子们都在吗？   - 他们已经等了半个小时了！
- Are the kids here ?   - They've been waiting for half an hour !
- 这是什么，法院的？   - 电梯帐单
- What is it, the court ?   - The elevator bill.
- 这是交钱的指令！   - 该死的电梯！
- It's an order to pay !   - That fucking elevator !
我才不要电梯，我不想为它付钱，我才不用它！
I don't want an elevator, I don't want to pay for it, I don't use it !
干嘛要把它发给我们？我们有律师的，我亲爱的朋友，维托利奥...
Why did they send it to us ? We have a lawyer, my dear friend, Vittorio...
他学的是教会法规！
He's got a degree in canon law !
他的头脑非常聪明
He's got a brain like this.
维托利奥是教皇的最后通谕的代笔人
Vittorio was the ghost-writer for the Pope's last encyclical.
- 好吧...   - 而且他不收费
- All right...   - And he's free.
- 我得去上课了   - 要确保能拿到薪水！
- I need to do my lesson.   - Make sure you get paid !
要是你不去找他们，我去！
If you don't ask them, I will !
嘘！求你把它放下来！我去找他们
Ssh ! Keep it down, please ! I'll tell them.
各位，抱歉我来晚了，我被一点小事缠住了
Guys, sorry I'm late, but I had a bit of a busy clay.
原因就不讲了... 好吧，把你们的书翻开到...
You don't need to know... Right, open your book at...
- 你们在抽大麻？   - 我们在等...
- Are you smoking a joint ?   - While we were waiting...
等什么等？马上给我扔了！
While you were waiting ? Put that out right now !
你们不是开玩笑吧？
Are you being serious ?
她平时跟戒毒的人打交道
She works with recovering addicts,
她会把这当作对她的挑衅，而且她是对的！
she'd see it as a provocation and she'd be right !
- 至少等到她离开！   - 我走了
- At least wait till she leaves !   - I'm going.
- 你们在抽大麻吗？   - 没有，有人在楼下煎东西
- Are you smoking a joint ?   - No, someone's frying downstairs...
你要确保能拿到薪水！
Make sure you get paid !
嗯，其实...
Yes, in fact...
我一直在想，在我们进行这三个月课程的同时
I was thinking, in parallel with the three-month course we're doing,
我们也许可以讨论下报酬的事，比如说...
we could also maybe begin a discourse about remuneration, let's say...
意思是...你们准备什么时候付我钱？
meaning... when are you going to pay me ?
教授，我们说过的，你要干到一半再说
Professor, we said before, you have to meet us halfway.
我已经干到一半了
I am meeting you halfway,
可你们每人欠我500多欧元
but you owe me more than 500 euros each.
这不是针对个人，我并不是对你们有想法
It's not personal, I've not got it in for you,
你们给我报酬是天经地义的事
it's a general thing to do with all of you.
- 毛里齐奥？   - 他在那边躺着呢
- Maurizio ?   - He's lying down over there.
那边，这么一小会，又一次？他不是玩真的吧！
Over there, a moment, again ? He cannot be serious !
他把这儿当旅馆了？
Does he think this apartment is a hotel ?
他跑过来，上了一节课，然后躺了下来！我是说...
He comes here, does a lesson, then lies down ! I mean...
- 毛里齐奥！   - 再给我五分钟，教授，请你...
- Maurizio !   - Five minutes more, Prof, please...
不，不，没有五分钟
No, no, no five minutes,
而且我告诉过你上床之前起码把牛仔裤脱了
and I'd asked you to at least take your jeans off when you get into bed.
请把门关上，外面光太强了！
Please ! Close the door, there's too much light coming in !
我的头脑要炸了，再给我五分钟就好
My head's bursting, five minutes and I'll be with you.
没有五分钟！起来跟别人一样去上你的课
No five minutes ! Get up and come for your lesson like everyone else.
真不敢相信！
Can you believe this ?
- 你们去哪？   - 时间到了，我约了6点钟去跳舞
- Where are you going ?   - Time's up, I've got dance at 6.
- 好吧，我们说好的事呢？   - 周三见
- All right, and what did we agree ?   - See you on Wednesday.
不，关于钱的
No, about the money.
教授，发生了危机，你没读报纸吗？找找看
Prof, there's a crisis, don't you read the papers ? Mark it down.
什么...？
What...?
等等，你们打算把毛里齐奥丢给我？
Hang on, are you leaving Maurizio with me ?
我跟维托利奥谈过了，不得不说他确实让我放心了
I spoke with Vittorio and I have to say he really reassured me,
因为他说交钱的指令并不是最终判决
because he says the order to pay isn't like a definitive sentence.
所以我们可以提出反对，多争取些时间
So we can oppose it and gain some time.
只是一桩小事，亲爱的。我会拿到我的合同，这样我们就能...
It's only a matter of clays, love, I'll get my contract and we can...
毛里齐奥，我觉得你最好去做次全面体检
Maurizio, I think you should go for a thorough general checkup,
因为从你睡觉的样子看，有可能是嗜睡症的初始阶段
because the way you fall asleep, it could be first-stage narcolepsy.
- 这不是玩笑，你懂的   - 我不觉得...
- It's serious, you know.   - I don't think so...
因为我今天早上6点才到家，累坏了。肯定是因为这个
because I got home at 6 this morning, exhausted. That must be it.
我理解，可你父母没说什么？
I understand, but don't your parents say anything ?
还有关于授课薪水的事...
About paying for the lessons too...
朱莉亚，毛里齐奥的父母死于一场空难
Giulia, Maurizio lost his parents in a plane crash,
所以你能想像他的情况有多糟
so you can imagine how serious the situation is,
这可怜的家伙必须在周末去端盘子才能付得出学费
the poor guy has to serve tables at the weekend to pay for his lessons,
告诉她
tell her.
我必须在周末端盘子
I have to serve tables at the weekend.
可他正计划付钱...告诉她
But he's planning to pay... Tell her.
我正计划付钱
I'm planning to pay.
总之，我之前想表达的意思是
Anyway, what I was trying to say earlier
这项研究的确是个了不起的成功
was the research really was a great success.
委员会立马就看出了
The commission saw right away
我发明的这个算法的革命性影响
the revolutionary impact of this algorithm
而它将会引发，我敢保证，一次科学巨震
that I invented and that will lead, I'm sure, to a scientific earthquake.
教授，吃饭时别说这些！
Prof, not at the table !
整个下午都有这种压抑的感觉
This agony has been going on in the background all afternoon,
合同、科研、巨震，呃！
the contract, the scientific research, the earthquake, eh !
对，没错，彼得罗，所有我们眼前的难题，你也是！
Yes, really, Pietro, with all the problems we have, you as well !
所以，根据薛定谔方程式
So, according to Schrodinger's equation,
我们可以毫无疑问地说这些粒子...
we can say without any doubt that the particles...
- 彼得罗，我得跟你谈谈   - 教授，我正考试呢...
- Pietro, I have to speak to you.   - Professor, I'm doing an exam...
我知道这个学生的情况。你还没准备好，很明显
I know what this student's like. You're not ready, obviously,
下学期再来吧
come back next session.
教授，我已经回答了所有的问题，我需要这次考试
Professor, I've answered all the questions, I need this exam.
我们家开了一间药店！我怎么跟我父亲说？
My family has a pharmacy ! What can I tell my father ?
我给你28分，别再碍我的事，行吗？
28 out of 30, to stop you breaking my balls ! All right ?
- 什么事？   - 我有两条消息给你
- What is it ?   - I've two bits of news for you,
一条是坏消息，另一条更糟
one is bad and the other is really shit,
因为委员会已经决定只对五项请求中的一项进行资助
because the commission has agreed to only one of the five requests
财政削减造成的
for financing because of the cutbacks.
这真是一场悲剧，尤其是对我的同事们，因为...
This is a tragedy, especially for my colleagues, because...
不，是你没得到。真正糟糕的消息是贾科梅蒂得到了
No, you don't get it, the really shit news is Giacometti got it.
贾科梅蒂得到了？
Giacometti got it ?
可我的研究有拿诺贝尔奖的希望！贾科梅蒂？
But my research could be Nobel material ! Giacometti ?
听着，彼得罗
Listen, Pietro,
他们根本就不理解你的研究，因为太深奥了
they understood nothing about your research because it's too difficult !
我同样也不理解！
I didn't understand anything about it either !
塞塔教授看上去像个傻瓜
Professor Seta looked like a fool,
因为他们不停地问啊问啊问那些我没法回答的问题
because they were asking and asking and asking things I couldn't answer.
教授，我们一起签的研究协议！
Professor, we both signed the research !
求你，你不能回避这些问题！
You can't not answer the questions, please !
你不明白！这是个政治问题
You don't understand ! It's a political problem.
你和那些极端天主教徒站在一起的决定
Your decision to line up with the Catholic extremists
是错的，而且毫无远见
was a mistake and very shortsighted.
教授，是你说你那个来自阿韦利诺的朋友笑了...
Professor, it was you who said your friend from Avellino had smiled...
- 与我无关   - 他是个老托洛茨基分子
- It was nothing to do with me.   - He's an old Trotskyite
来自现属左翼自由联盟阵营中的共产党！
from the Communist Party who's in Sinistra e Libertà now !
我有尝试和他交谈
I even tried speaking to him,
我说，我们有共同的普适价值观
I said, we have some Catholic values in common,
你知道他说什么吗？滚开！所以我就说，如果你让我滚开
you know what he said ? Fuck off ! So I said, if you say fuck off,
那你为什么不滚，你这个老王八！接下来事情就有点失控了
Then why don't you fuck off, you old bugger ! And then things got a bit out of control.
教授，这是不是说不会有长期合同了？
Professor, does this mean no long-term contract ?
他们连一年的合同都不会给你！
They won't even give you a year's contract !
每月那500欧元对我很重要，教授！
Those 500 euros a month kept me going Professor !
我已经37岁了，现在我还能开始做什么呢？
I'm 37, what can I start doing now ?
稍等，我接下电话
Wait, I need to answer this.
喂，你好，我是马尔凯托！
Yes, hello, Marchetto !
怎么说呢？我们开始了一项未知的...
What can I say ? We proceed into the unknown...
我想问你来着，你把船的泊位订好了吗？
I wanted to ask you, did you book the mooring for the boat ?
安乔莱托真把事情搞砸了。你知道这傻缺干了什么事吗？
Angioletto really messed things up. Do you know what the dickhead did ?
- 彼得罗，你在卫生间里吗？   - 对
- Pietro, you in the bathroom ?   - Yes.
- 还要很久吗？   - 不，我好了。马上出来
- You going to be long ?   - No, I'm finished. Coming.
- 你讲话怪怪的   - 没，没有
- You sound strange.   - No, no.
- 你哭了？   - 没，没有
- Have you been crying ?   - No, no,
我估计是你肥皂的PH值不适合...
it's the PH of this soap of yours, I think...
彼得罗，别像个傻瓜，是你工作上出了什么问题吗？
Pietro, don't be an asshole, has something happened at work ?
不，不是...我原想和你谈一下...
No, no... I wanted to talk to you for a minute...
你的合同出问题了？
Are there problems with your contract ?
没有。只不过新合同上有一点点...
No. It's just that the new contract has kind of...
他们给没给你签新合同？
Did they give you a new contract or not ?
如果你只想要简单的回答有或没有...
If you want a simple yes or no...
- 有或没有？   - 有！
- Yes or no ?   - Yes!
有，是一份全日制合同
Yes, and a full-time contract.
我本想给你个惊喜，可被你毁了。不过那又如何？
I wanted to surprise you, but you spoiled it. But so what ?
那他们有没有告诉你每月付你多少钱？
Did they tell you what they'll pay you a month ?
嗯，这不是你想要多少就多少的。。。
Well, that's not something you ask...
对，当然，别担心...
No, of course, don't worry about it...
别期望太高，他们又不是让我当院长
Don't expect too much, it's not like they made me rector.
好吧，了解，不过至少有1500欧元，是吗？别吊我胃口！
All right, I get it, but at least 1,500, no ? For fuck's sake !
当然，可能还再多点
Sure, maybe a little bit more.
- 2000？   - 差不多
- 2,000 ?   - Sure.
等等，1500还是2000？
Hang on, 1,500 or 2,000 ?
按加权平均来算，差不多1800欧元
Do a weighted mean, kind of 1,800.
好吧，这样的话我们就能付得起电梯费了
All right, this way we can pay the elevator.
对，没错
Yeah, sure.
- 而且我们能雇得起真正的律师了   - 没错
- Then we'll hire a real lawyer.   - Sure.
到那天，再买台洗碗机
And while we're at it, a dishwasher.
好的，不过我们不能重蹈别人的覆辙
Yeah, but let's not make that classic mistake people make,
有些人一拿到钱
where as soon as they get some money,
- 就花得精光   - 是的。我们到那边去
- they spend it.   - Sure. Let's go through there.
去那边？都9点了，我约了乔吉奥和马蒂亚
Through there ? It's 9, I've got to meet Giorgio and Mattia.
一会再去吧！
So go later !
不，这次肾上腺素的下降使我体内缺乏钾离子...
No, this drop in adrenaline has lowered my potassium...
稍后你可以来份香蕉奶昔
You can make a banana shake after.
之后我会逐渐衰弱，出现大规模脱盐...
Then I'll go in asthenia, major saline deficiency...
- 彼得罗，你在耍我！   - 我来了！
- Pietro, you're breaking my balls !   - I'm coming.
不过，坦白说，别对表现有过多期望
But, hands up, don't expect too much of a performance
只是纯粹庆祝一下，做不了什么花样！
which is going to be purely celebratory, no fancy acrobatics !
我能跟你说什么呢？
What can I tell you ?
根据你说的情况，好像挺复杂的
From what you say, it sounds really complicated.
这差不多就是海勒里安悖论
I'd almost say a Hellerian paradox.
乔吉奥，我失业了，身无分文，你却说什么海勒里安？
Giorgio, I'm jobless, penniless and you say it's Hellerian ?
- 这就是场悲剧！   - 听着
- It's a tragedy !   - Look,
它本身并没有多严重
in itself it doesn't have too high a gravity index.
是你说谎把事情搞复杂了，让你陷入被动
It's the lying which complicates it, given your domestic situation.
我知道，马蒂亚，不过在奉献了七年之后
I know, Mattia, but after seven years of sacrifices,
- 让我怎么能告诉她实情呢？   - 是吗？
- how could I tell her the truth ?   - Yes ?
- 满足她   - 干嘛提到长期合同？
- Fill her up.   - Why mention a long-term contract ?
好吧，顺嘴溜出来的
Well, that bullshit just slipped out.
各位，我还有项法院指令要去付费，他们准备拿走我的东西做抵押
Guys, I have a court order to pay, they're going to seize my things,
家里紧张到了极点...
and it's all really stressful at home...
我懂，不过空悲切有什么用
I know, but moaning won't help.
各位，这太可悲了！我意思是，看看你们自己！
Guys, this is pathetic ! I mean, look at yourselves !
我可不想走你们这条路！
I don't want to end up like you !
国际知名的拉丁学者在一个加油站里
Internationally acclaimed Latin scholars standing in a gas station
为了挣钱给一个锡兰人打工
working for a Singhalese guy who pays you cash.
彼得罗，注意你说阿里·汗先生的言辞
Pietro, watch what you say about Mister Ali Khan,
他在我们非常困难的时候给了我们信心
who had faith in us at a very difficult moment.
他是个可敬的人，有着不容质疑的美德和慷慨大度...
He's a lovely man, of undoubted morality and generosity...
喂，毛里齐奥！我花钱就是让你站那聊天来着？
Oi ! Do I pay you to stand there and chat ?
抱歉，阿里·汗先生。这位先生马上就走
Sorry, Mr. Ali Khan. The gentleman is leaving.
快走，不然他生起气来有得搞
Go, or he'll be pissed and rightly so.
你怎么说锡兰语？
You speak Singhalese ?
好吧，要是你懂梵文，两者差不了多少
Well, if you know Sanskrit, it all falls into place.
- 205欧元   - 给你
- 205 euros.   - There you go.
- 谢谢你   - 谢谢，晚安
- Thank you.   - Thank you. Good night.
- 那是毛利齐奥？   - 谁？
- Was that Maurizio ?   - Who ?
- 他刚刚付了多少钱？   - 205欧元
- What did he just pay ?   - 205 euros.
两...
Two...
安全帽，马蒂亚，安全帽！
The helmet, Mattia, the helmet !
毛里齐奥！毛里齐奥！
Maurizio ! Maurizio !
该死的！
Fucking hell
教授！你在干嘛...？
Professor ! What are you doing...?
- 这个时候还出来骑车？   - 毛里齐奥
- Out on a bike at this hour ?   - Maurizio,
马上靠边，因为我们得谈谈！
pull over right now because you and I have to speak !
这是怎么回事？我跟每个人都说你很穷
What's going on ? I've been telling everyone you're poor
而你却在开着宇宙飞船兜风？
and you're driving around in a spaceship ?
- 我记得你是个服务生？   - 对，不过我不常干
- I thought you were a waiter ?   - Yeah, I don't do it very often.
我父亲有家餐饮公司
My father's got a catering company.
你父亲？我记得你父亲已经去世了！
Your father ? I thought your father was dead !
没！我们吵了一架，我说：“就我而言，你已经死了”
No ! We argued and I said, "As far as I'm concerned, you're dead."
- 但后来我们...   - 好吧，但是这有很大的区别！
- But then we made up...   - OK, but there's a big difference !
毛里齐奥，马上靠边
Maurizio, pull over now
把欠我的钱给我，因为我看见你花200欧元加了汽油
and give me what you owe me, because I saw you pay 200 euros for gas,
- 我看见你了！   - 我不能停下，不然我就上不了名单
- I saw you !   - I can't, I'll miss the guest list.
- 什么？   - 在市中心大厅，1点钟就要关门
- What ?   - At Central, it closes at one.
已经很晚了，我必须过去
It's late, I need to go.
- 就这样，教授！我们走了！   - 毛里齐奥！
- Great, Professor ! On you go !   - Maurizio !
过来！毛里齐奥！毛里齐奥！
Come here ! Maurizio ! Maurizio !
- 毛里齐奥！   - 太好了，教授！你也来了！
- Maurizio !   - Great, Professor ! Here as well !
这顶安全帽挺配你的！款式真好！
That helmet suits you ! What style !
你下来，我们得谈谈！下来！
Get down here, we need to speak ! Get down !
教授，一点零钱别那么大惊小怪
Professor, what a fuss over some loose change.
我现在就给你，让你高兴一下
I'll give you it now just to keep you happy.
- 多少钱？   - 500欧元
- How much is it ?   - 500 euros.
加上30欧元跟过来的费用，这是必须的
Plus 30 euros to get in here, which has to be added.
不行，我还得买单呢
I can't, I have to pay for my table.
- 我只能给你一半   - 不行！一半不行，给我全额
- I can give you half.   - No ! Not half, give me all of it.
好吧，我周三给全。可以吧，教授！
All right, I'll give you all of it on Wednesday. Great, Professor !
好吧。给我一半。先给一半，另一半周三给
All right. Give me half. Give me half and the rest on Wednesday.
而且我跟你说，你是个非常不诚实的人
And let me tell you, you're a profoundly dishonest person,
你很粗鲁，而且你是个大骗子！
you're rude, and you're a big liar!
你想毁了我这个晚上？放松一下吧
You want to ruin my night ? Relax a minute,
看你这样子，汗都湿透了
you're a mess, you're all sweaty.
我浑身是汗！这鬼地方像地狱一样，足足有40度
I'm sweaty ! This place is hellish, with a 40 degrees temperature range,
- 我已经要受不了了   - 没错，把这个喝了吧
- and I am really, really jumpy.   - Exactly, so drink this.
- 这是什么？   - 这是什么？这是鸡尾酒！
- What is it ?   - What is it ? It's a cocktail !
好吧，我只是太渴了
All right, just because I'm really thirsty.
这算我的。要100欧元呢
It's on me. It costs 100 euros.
这可以消除你的顾虑，你所有的担心
It'll get rid of all your worries, all your concerns,
算我的
it's on me.
这个很淡，而且有点水果味...
It's quite light and it's a bit fruity...
- 不好意思，这为什么要100欧元？   - 没错，教授！
- Sorry, why does it cost 100 euros ?   - Yeah, Professor !
抱歉，你在干什么？
I'm sorry, what are you doing ?
我在小便！想睡觉就到外面去
I'm peeing ! Go outside if you want to collapse.
- 毛里齐奥！   - 好极了，教授！你去哪了？
- Maurizio !   - Great, Professor ! Where were you ?
- 那是什么？你让我吸毒了？   - 再来一杯振作一下？
- What was that ? Did you drug me ?   - Have another one to pick you up !
毛里齐奥，你真阴险！你差点杀了我！
Maurizio, you're dangerous ! You could have killed me !
杀你！这可是顶级货
Kill you ! That's top-quality stuff.
顶级？这就是垃圾合成品
Quality ? It's synthetic rubbish,
只是麻黄素合剂！
some ephedrine concoction !
这杯垃圾里有两片药，每片50欧元！
That rubbish contained two pills that cost 50 euros each !
毛里齐奥，我是个好人，可我要是陷进去... 50欧元？
Maurizio, I'm a nice guy, but if I lose it... 50 euros ?
这是欺诈！做一片这种药根本要不了2欧元
That's fraud ! Making one of those can't cost more than two euros.
好吧，下堂课，教我们怎么做它，我们弄它1公斤！
Well, next lesson, teach us how to make it and we'll make a kilo!
好极了，教授！
Great, Professor !
迪斯科药丸
DISCO PILLS
贩卖毒品的后果
CONSEQUENCES OF SELLING DRUGS
合法贩卖毒品
SELLING DRUGS LEGALLY
精神药剂
SMART DRUGS
毒品：意大利精神药剂警报，280种新型毒品
Drugs: Alarm smart drug in Italy, 280 new drugs
效果等同于传统毒品的合法精神类药剂开始流行
SPREAD OF LEGAL SMART DRUGS THAT HAVE THE SAME EFFECTS AS TRADITIONAL DRUGS
警察束手无策，他们不能拘捕我们
THE POLICE CAN'T DO ANYTHING, THEY CAN'T ARREST US
- 一种不合法，一种合法   - 这是欧洲立法上的漏洞
- ONE'S ILLEGAL, ONE'S NOT   - IT'S A LEGISLATIVE GAP IN EUROPE
欧盟成员能做的就是不断把新制剂补充到清单里
ALL THE E.U. CAN DO IS CONSTANTLY UPDATE THE LIST OF NEW SUBSTANCES
- 彼得罗？   - 嗯
- Pietro ?   - Yeah.
你还没睡啊？在干什么呢？
You're still up ? What are you doing ?
刚才上了会网...随便看看
I was just surfing a bit... randomly.
至少保证把浏览历史删了
Make sure you delete the history at least.
- 你脸上那是什么？   - 嗯？
- What's that on your face ?   - Eh ?
- 你脸上   - 哦，没什么，只是画了个哨子
- On your face.   - Oh no nothing it's just a click.
你干嘛在脸上画个鸡巴？
Why have you got a dick drawn on your face ?
因为看着挺好玩的，不是吗？
Because it seemed like a fun thing to do. No ?
啊，是你？彼得罗，快点，我只有五分钟的时间
Ah, it's you ? Pietro, quick, I've only got a five-minute break.
不，我的研究快有结果了
No, it's that I've almost finished my research.
算法研究？
The study on the algorithm ?
你再次从TAAR1的三级构架中
You set out again from the tertiary structure
提出了功能更高效的
of the TAAR1 to get a better score function
内源性兴奋剂。我的天呐，干得漂亮
for its endogenous agonists. Bloody hell, well done.
真不错，可为什么要带给我？
Good work, but why bring it to me ?
没什么，嗯，因为五年前你也参与了项目的启动，我想...
No, well, because you were there at the start 5 years ago, I thought...
现在我在从事别的
Now I'm doing something else.
听着，阿尔贝托，要是我跟你说C11H15NO2，你怎么讲？
Listen, Alberto, if I said to you C11 H15 N O2, what would you say ?
5分钟时间意味着300秒，我还得撒尿
5 minutes' break means 300 seconds and I need to pee.
- 要不了多久。C11H15NO2   - 是塞塔教授发给你的？
- It won't take long. C11 H15 N O2.   - Did Professor Seta send you ?
告诉他我不会在任何东西上面签字！再也不会！
Tell him I won't put my name to anything ! Never again !
这和塞塔一点关系也没有。C11H15NO2
It's nothing to do with Seta. C11 H15 N O2.
好吧，这是作用于血清素系统的精神类药物
All right, it's a psychotropic that acts on the serotonergic system.
- 还有呢？   - 还有？什么？还有就是它是非法的！
- And ?   - And ? What ? And it's illegal !
要是我替你把它弄成合法的呢？
What if I make it legal for you ?
阿尔贝托，阿尔贝托，等等！
Alberto, Alberto, wait !
好的，好的。抱歉，抱歉，抱歉。真的...我不了解你
Yes, yes. Sorry, sorry, sorry. Really... I don't understand you.
不，彼得罗！你不能在这儿。我没兴趣，告诉你...
No, Pietro ! You can't be in here. I'm not interested, I told you...
阿尔贝托，阿尔贝托，他们拒绝资助我的研究
Alberto, Alberto, they refused to fund my research.
我已经快要成功了，算法是可行的
I'd almost finished, the algorithm was working.
可是弄出一个你不能利用的理论制剂公式有什么用呢？
But why have a theoretical molecule program if you can't use it ?
没错！所以你就想到去弄一种精神类药物！
Sure ! So you thought, I'll theorize a psychotropic one !
阿尔贝托，我们比别人聪明得多
Alberto, we're more intelligent than the others.
要是我们一起合作就能挣很多钱！
If we worked together we could made a pile of money !
彼得罗，最多六个月我就会成为这里的服务生
Pietro, maximum six months I'll be working as a waiter here.
小费，一周工作六天，一个月700欧元！你明白吗？
Tips, one clay off a week and 700 euros a month ! Do you get it ?
我能帮你在半个小时里挣到700欧元
I'll help you earn 700 euros in half an hour.
你洗盘子的时候好好想一想吧。我出去了
While you're washing the plates, think about it. I'll be outside.
我在洗这些东西，我在洗这些东西！去你的！
I'm washing them, I'm washing them ! Fuck off !
听着，我会把我所有处方级的讲义分享给你
Look, I'll spare you all the lectures on the ethical level,
因为当我被赶出大学的时候我就放弃了伦理
because I abandoned ethics when they kicked me out of university.
我开始变得现实。我不想去监狱！
I'm being practical. I don't want to go to jail !
阿尔贝托，罪犯才去监狱，你和我是罪犯吗？
Alberto, criminals go to jail, are you and I criminals ?
根据我的算法得到的制剂不在政府的清单上
With the algorithm I make a molecule that's not on the Ministry list,
你来生产
and you produce it.
我们一起做出最好的药剂，而且完全合法
Together we make the best substance ever and we do it all legally.
我为什么要这么做？
Why would I do something like that ?
因为你是一名大学教授，你不该受到这种待遇
Because you're a university professor and you don't deserve this life.
- 你脸上是什么？   - 一个鸡巴剩下的部分
- What's that on your face ?   - What's left of a dick.
这是不可擦的笔... 算了，我们别分心
These indelible pens that... All right, let's not get distracted.
听着，我们得组建一个帮派
Listen, we're going to form a gang.
- 帮派？   - 帮派
- A gang ?   - A gang.
干非法销售？不行，没人会信我们，不！
Of pushers ? We can't, we wouldn't be credible, no !
不行，没人相信我们
No, we're not credible.
但我们能够变得可信，而且我已经找到了合适人选...
But we could become credible and I've got the right person...
...于是我为了不出卖朋友而蹲了两年监狱
...So I did two years' prison so as not to grass a friend.
出来后就跟着我叔叔干，直到他死于三个月前...
I got out, went to work with my uncle until he died three months ago...
- 啊，抱歉   - 没事，他没遭受痛苦
- Ah, I'm sorry.   - No, he didn't suffer,
刀子捅得非常准，就在颈动脉这儿
they knifed him really accurately, here on the carotid.
下手的那家伙从事的是某种老式在线扑克游戏的行当
And the guy that did it was right, some old online poker business.
当事情一团糟的时候，他的子女为遗嘱吵个不休
That's when it got messy, his children fighting over the will,
在法律层面上为了遗产争得很激烈，家家如此
a bitter legal quarrel over the inheritance, families are like that.
- 为了钱而争吵   - 抱歉，你刚才说什么？
- An argument about money.   - Sorry, what did you say ?
子女们开始争吵，都是和钱有关
The children started fighting, it always happens with money.
- 你刚才说“法律层面上争得很激烈”   - 是吗？我也不知道是什么意思
- You said "bitter legal quarrel".   - Me ? I don't know what that means.
- 你可是研究生   - 我不是研究生
- You're a graduate.   - I'm not a graduate.
我很清楚。我不要研究生
I was clear. I don't take graduates.
我不是！我在中学就因为卖毒品被开除了
I'm not ! I got kicked out of middle school for selling dope.
- 你让人无法相信   - 那我干嘛会在这儿？
- You can't be trusted.   - Why would I be here, then ?
- 你是这周第三位   - 我不是研究生！
- You're the third this week.   - I'm not a graduate!
好吧，我是，但我为这种幼稚的错误感到遗憾
All right, I am, but it was a youthful mistake that I regret.
我请求放弃我的学历
I'm asking to renounce my academic qualifications.
两周内，我会回到小学学历
In two weeks, I'll be back to grade 5 level.
我可以把所有论文给你看
I can show you all the paperwork.
- 你在这做事就不会干净了   - 所以我来了
- You get your hands dirty here.   - That's why I'm here.
我不需要一个只在那看书的人。明白吗？
I don't need people who are always reading. Is that clear ?
- 你看你是个好孩子   - 不！别叫我好孩子！
- You can see you're a good kid.   - No ! Don't call me a good kid !
我可是很危险的
I'm really very dangerous,
我时不时会做出一些无法预料的事
from one moment to another I might do something unexpected...
好。那么？
Yes. Well ?
安德里亚·德·桑蒂斯，人类学家
Andrea de Santis, anthropologist.
他是萨皮恩扎大学的知名人物
He was a big shot at Sapienza University.
那张票据很重要，是吗？我很抱歉
That was an important bill, wasn't it ? I'm really sorry,
我不知道刚才脑子怎么想的。这就是那张票据
I don't know what came over me. It was a bill,
不过重要的是数字，你可以认得出来...
but the important thing is the number, you can trace it...
把PDF文件发给我重新打印一份。我很抱歉
Send me the PDF and I'll reprint it. I'm very sorry.
你在干什么？你明白你不适合干这事
What are you doing ? You can see you're not cut out for it.
我知道。不过我正在度过一个难关
I know. But I'm going through a difficult period.
听着，孩子，积累点经验
Listen, kid, get a bit of experience,
找点麻烦，混迹街头，然后可以回来
get into trouble, live on the street, and then maybe come back.
好，谢谢你的建议
Yes, thanks for the advice.
在2007年财政削减之前
Before the cuts in 2007,
安德里亚是意大利顶尖的文化人类学专家之一
Andrea was one of Italy's leading experts in cultural anthropology.
他对人类学科的整体研究
His works on the holistic study of humanity
已经被翻译成50种语言
have been translated into 50 languages.
安德里亚会改变我们
Andrea will transform us.
没有哪一类人性是他不知道或在某种程度上模仿不了的
There's no human category he doesn't know and can't emulate in some way.
他会帮我们融入犯罪的世界
He'll fit us into the world of crime.
那我们怎么进行销售呢？
What will we do about sales ?
我们需要擅长夜间活动的人
We need someone who's good at night.
我有两个人选，他们干了多年的夜活
I've got two guys, they've been night people for years.
他们对周围的道路也很熟悉
They know their way round the street as well,
我是说，什么都见识过的人，嗯！相信我
I mean, people who have seen it all, eh ! Trust me.
- 需要什么？   - 你能帮我检查下轮胎吗？
- Yes ?   - Can you check my tires ?
检查下我的轮胎...尽管有点绕，我始终觉得
Check my tires... Despite the racket, I've always found it fascinating
盎格鲁撒克逊人说出来的本地方言让人陶醉
when the Anglo-Saxon contaminates the vernacular.
你他妈在说什么？
What the fuck are you saying ?
很明显，这只会发生在文盲身上...
Obviously, this occurs in barely literate environments...
我真想把他脑袋砸碎
I'm going to crack his skull.
马蒂亚，马蒂亚，这位强壮的男士好像对我充满了敌意
Mattia, Mattia, the brawny gentleman seems to me to be hostile.
我想友情提醒你，就算是暴力威胁也是犯罪...
I'd like to remind you that even the threat of violence is a crime...
哦，滚犊子吧你！
Oh, fuck off, you !
接下来是阿图罗·弗兰提尼
Then there's Arturo Frantini.
每当发现古罗马的东西时，他都会出现进行监督
Whenever they find something from Ancient Rome, he comes to supervise.
他是古罗马考古专业研究生，擅长考古制图
He's a classics archeology graduate specialized in archeological mapping.
没人比他更了解罗马
Nobody knows Rome like he does.
抱歉，抱歉，请把它关掉吧！
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, switch this thing off, please !
这是狄奥多西一世的纪念碑牌匾
It's a memorial plaque to Theodosius the Great.
你不能用钻头在上面打孔！
You can't use a pneumatic drill on it !
抱歉，先生...
Sorry, sir, I got caught up...
他很穷，11年的短期合同，跟他父母住在一起
He's poor, 11 years of short-term contracts, lives with his parents.
- 先生，您不吃东西吗？   - 不，不
- Sir, you not eating ?   - No, no.
天太热了，而且我担心体重会增加
It's too hot and I'm scared of putting on weight.
当我年轻的时候他们觉得我肚子里有毛病
When I was a teenager they thought I might have celiac disease,
- 直到医生决定...   - 好吧，我知道了
- and until the doctors decide...   - All right, I get it.
没事，真的，真的，我很好
No, really, really, I'm fine.
这份是加了炒蛋的
This is the one with omelet.
你老婆在里面加了洋葱？
Your wife makes it with onion ?
好吧，不是对她无礼，也许我可以破下例
Well, not to be rude to her, maybe I can make an exception.
我们干嘛要用到考古学家？
Why do we need an archeologist ?
我们需要阿图罗开卡车
We need Arturo for the truck.
卡车？
The truck ?
阿图罗有一辆考古部门的车可以开
Arturo has the use of a vehicle from the Archeology Department.
可以进入城里任何地方，钻石大道，市中心
Total access to all parts of town, diamond lanes, downtown,
甚至夜里还能开进小路
even the bypass at night.
警察不会阻拦考古部门的卡车
The police won't stop an Archeology Department truck.
没错。那财务方面呢？
Of course. What about all the financial part ?
我在考虑马迪尼蒂。管理经济学专业
I was thinking of Martinetti. Management economics.
- 马迪尼蒂在挪威呢   - 他在奥斯陆拿到教师资格了？
- Martinetti's in Norway.   - He got the teaching post in Oslo ?
没，他在渔船上
No, he's on the fishing boats,
在北极圈一待就是六个月，整个鳕鱼季
six months in the Arctic Circle, the whole cod season.
很好！
Good!
还有波内利。为什么不，动态微观经济学专业，不行吗？
There's Bonelli. Why not, dynamic microeconomics, no ?
- 不，波内利做事从不考虑后果   - 那是过去式了！他现在好多了
- No, Bonelli's a loose cannon.   - Long ago ! He's better now.
他正在做经济学理论研究而且搞得不错
He's doing important economic-math research and it's going pretty well.
- 两千   - 亮牌
- 2,000.   - I'll see you.
我也亮
Me too.
好了，各位，这都是需要数学的，所以别抱怨
Now, guys, this is all just math, so don't complain.
- 一对   - 三个头
- Two pairs.   - Three of a kind.
- 同花顺   - 三个头？
- Straight flush.   - Three of a kind ?
两张A也想赢两千，你真能诈啊！
2,000 with two aces, what kind of bluff is that ?
什么诈？这是数学。是不是有52张牌？
What bluff ? This is math. There are 52 cards ?
那么就有52个阶乘因子。除以52
So there are 52 factorial divisions. divided by 52,
减去5的阶乘，再除以5的阶乘，就得到2698590
minus factorial 5, divided by factorial 5, which makes 2,698,590,
好吧，我理解你的同花顺，不过三个头有点奇怪
all right. I understand your flush, but the three of a kind is strange.
巴尔托洛梅奥，如果这就是你不给钱的借口，那小心点
Bartolomeo, if this is an excuse not to pay, be careful.
当然不会
Of course not.
可要是我说三个头有点奇怪，就是因为确实奇怪
But if I say the three of a kind is strange, it's because it is.
你他妈在说什么？
What the fuck are you saying ?
抱歉，你是学推论统计学的？
Excuse me, do you do inferential statistics ?
随机变数？计算概率？
Random variables ? Calculating probability ?
我可不这么认为
I don't really think so.
- 算了，总共多少？   - 七千
- Anyway, what's the total ?   - 7,000.
七千。我全付了。尽管我还是保持怀疑...
7,000. I'll pay it all. Though I still have my doubts...
不过我想说：我们再多玩一局，赢的人全拿走？
But let me say this: let's play one more hand, winner takes all ?
巴尔托洛梅奥，在这个夜晚变味之前把钱付清！
Bartolomeo, pay up before the evening turns sour !
你直接说不行就是了
You could just say no.
我没有现金，我可以给你远期支票
I haven't got cash, I'll give you a post-dated check.
- 最好是现金   - 现金最好，好
- Cash is better.   - Cash is better, yes.
哦，你太过分了！
Oh, you're overdoing it !
巴尔托洛梅奥！把钱给我们！
Bartolomeo ! Give us the money !
- 宝贝，你又干了些什么？   - 别生气
- Baby, what have you done now ?   - Don't be angry with me.
你老爸，恕我直言，连反话都听不懂！该死的！
Your father, with all due respect, has no sense of irony ! Fuck !
我们只是在玩牌...然后他有点疯了，疯了...
We were just playing cards... And at certain point, he went mad, mad...
彼得罗，你他妈在这干嘛？
Pietro, what the fuck are you doing here ?
- 进来   - 好的
- Get in.   - Yeah.
我该怎么跟你说呢？你不能在纸牌游戏里做运算
How can I tell you this ? You can't count the cards in poker.
碰上你这类人我就泡汤
It's people like you I screw.
- 你好，弗兰提尼教授   - 波内利教授
- Hello, Professor Frantini.   - Professor Bonelli.
好了我们该走了，要是他们上了保时捷我们就不好办了
Ok we should go now, because if they get the Porsches we'll be in the shit.
- 毫无疑问   - 对
- Undoubtedly.   - Yes.
首先，我要感谢乔吉奥和马蒂亚
First of all, I'd like to thank Giorgio and Mattia
允许我们使用这个地方...
for letting us use this place...
老天，各位！你买了个加油站？
Bloody hell, guys ! You bought a gas station ?
没有，它是属于阿里·汗先生的
No, it belongs to Mister Ali Khan,
他提供仓库给他的工人住...
he uses the warehouses for his workers...
啊，这真得很有趣，因为我刚好跟一个姑娘住一起
Ah, this is very interesting, because I've just been living with a girl
她来自一个辛蒂马戏团家庭...关系挺难维持的
from a Sinti circus family... a difficult relationship,
因为他们非常传统
because they're very traditional,
把钱看得很重...
really attached to money...
打住，要是你想搬这儿来住
Stop there, if you're thinking of moving in here,
我必须得阻止你，因为你不能这么做
I have to stop you because you can't.
- “我必须得阻止你”！   - 你不能在这吸烟
- "I have to stop you" !   - You can't smoke here.
- 这里到处是易燃品   - 马蒂亚！   - 绝对禁止
- It's all inflammable.   - Mattia ! - Absolutely forbidden.
好吧，也许我们以后再研究住房问题
All right, maybe we can sort out the lodgings problem later.
你们可能在想为什么我把大家召集过来
You'll be wondering why I asked you all to come here.
我知道你想干什么
I know what you're up to.
但说真的，彼得罗
But really, Pietro,
在国会前由研究员组织的另一场
another demo by researchers on short-term contracts
为了短期合同的示威
outside Parliament,
- 我们在受到最后的打击后...   - 不，阿图罗
- after the last beating we got...   - No, Arturo.
我喊你们来不是为了另一场反对削减研究经费的示威
I didn't ask you here for yet another demo against research cuts.
更确切地说我喊你们来是因为我不想再这么干了
I asked you here precisely because I don't want to do that again.
你们是周边最聪明的人
You're the greatest minds around
而你们却生活在社会的边缘！
and you're living on the fringes of society !
我们懂的唯一一件事就是做研究。而他们还不让我们做
The only thing we know how to do is study. And they won't let us.
现在，我已经找到一条路来拿到我们应得的东西
Well, I've worked out a way to get what we deserve.
- 再来一次示威！   - 不，阿图罗
- Back to the demo again !   - No, Arturo,
我们成立一个帮派。我们在市场上推销一种新型毒品
We form a gang. We put a new drug on the market,
不是目前在俱乐部里的那种垃圾
not the shit they have in clubs now,
而是从未有过的最好的产品！
but the best product there's ever been !
你们认为呢？
What do you think ?
打扰一下，你是说我可能要两，两个晚上
Excuse me, are you saying that if I for two, two, nights,
在那根容易被人发现的柱子后面睡在这么小的床垫上？
with a mattress this size went behind that pillar someone would notice ?
巴尔托洛梅奥，得了，我们正在这做一项重要的决定
Bartolomeo, come on, we're making an important decision here.
我全力支持你，这个为了我们自己的计划很吸引我
I'm with you 100%, this setting up for ourselves really appeals to me.
你们都知道我接受的教育都是基于早期奥地利自由主义的
You all know my training was all based on early Austrian liberalism,
冯·哈耶克和冯·米塞斯...
Von Hayek e Von Mises...
那有个水箱！我在水箱后面谁能看得见？
There's the tank ! Who'd see me behind the tank ?
- 好啦，各位   - 抱歉，彼得罗...
- Come on, guys.   - Excuse me, Pietro...
只是想证实我的理解无误
just to check I've understood.
你是想组建一个从事非法销售的帮派，就像美剧里那样？
You want to set up a gang of pushers like in the American TV shows ?
我不确定这个主意是否完全符合刑法
I'm not sure this initiative is entirely in line with the penal code.
对，符合
Yes, it is,
因为我已经研究出一种制剂符合意大利法律
because I've theorized a molecule that for Italian law is legal.
现在先别管什么愚蠢的合法性了。我们一步步来
Never mind this silly legal stuff for now. Let's go step by step.
第一步。启动。巴尔托洛梅奥，我需要一份详细的财务计划
Phase 1. Start-up. Bartolomeo, I need a detailed financial plan,
我必须了解这样是不是能够发展得下去
I have to understand if this is economically sustainable.
成本、收入、利润，所有的东西
Costs, income, profit margins, everything.
首先，我们从笛卡尔模型开始...
To start with, we'll begin with a simple Cartesian model...
...在一套数学系统内，为了让事情简单
...within a math system that, to keep things simple,
我们称之为“市场”
we'll call "the market".
在建立供需曲线之后
Having established the supply and demand curves,
我们就拥有了去获得启动资金的基础
we have the basis on which to get start-up funds.
别摆出那堆臭脸，因为我们没什么好担心的
Don't make those faces because there's nothing to worry about.
发行股票要有必要的时间，我们知道
The issuing of shares takes the time it takes, we know that,
不过还有股权清盘以及/或者兑现
but there's the liquidation and/or cashing in of stock options,
我们有信用额度，我们有预开支票的可能性
we have credit lines, we have the possibility of pre-billing,
我们能拿到贷款，提前拿到买断补偿金...
we can get a loan, an advance on our severance packages...
...再抵押...
...remortgaging...
...一些个人存款...
...some personal savings...
从你们家里借钱...
loans from your families...
没了
nothing.
好吧，我会带点钱过来
All right, I'll come up with something.
该死！
Fuck !
- 你疯了吗？   - 是我
- Are you mad ?   - It's me.
- 你在干什么？   - 我得见你
- What are you doing ?   - I needed to see you.
- 怎么，你要钱？   - 不，不！好吧，就要一点儿
- What, you need money ?   - No, no ! Well, a little.
- 救命！   - 嘘！你疯了吗？闭嘴！
- Help !   - Shhh ! Are you mad ? Shut up!
给我出去，巴尔托洛梅奥。我什么都不会给你的！
Get out of here, Bartolomeo. I'm giving you nothing !
你除了会输光。你怎么指望在纸牌游戏里做运算
You'd only lose it. You can't count the cards in poker.
先不说可以这种事实，而且也不止我一个人这么说
Apart from the fact you can, and it's not just me who says so,
不过现在都无关紧要了
but that's irrelevant now.
这次是为了一个与我大学同事有关的项目，实实在在的
It's for a project with my university colleagues, it's something concrete.
你总是这么说。我知道你只对我的钱有兴趣
You always say that. I know you're only interested in me for my money.
不是这样的！这太让我伤心了！
That's not true ! That's hurtful to me !
我正要和你一起做点什么，朝前看
I'm building something with you, looking ahead.
那就娶我吧！
So marry me !
天啊，今晚你真漂亮
God, you're beautiful tonight.
- 你真得愿意娶我？   - 再说吧，听着...
- You'll really marry me ?   - We'll see, listen...
一万欧元现金，但得是小面额的
10,000 euros in cash, but small denomination notes,
不要那些500欧元面值的，大家不喜欢那种
not those 500-euro ones, people don't like them.
第二步。原材料。丁香酚，任何丁香制品里都能找到
Phase 2. Raw materials. Eugenol, you find it in anything made with cloves.
我们需要不少。香波、空气清新剂、精油等等
We need a lot. Shampoo, air fresheners, essential oils.
我们来进行提炼
We'll extract it.
啊，你自己做的啊？真是太好了
Ah, you make your own ? Good to know.
我现在可以告诉我老婆了，她对丁香很着迷
I can tell my wife now, she's obsessed with cloves.
她让我给她买一些
I'll get some supplies in, I'll take 50.
丁香酚经过氢氧化钾和戊醇的处理后
Eugenol treated with potassium hydroxide and amyl alcohol
就变成异丁香酚
becomes isoeugenol.
要把它变成MD2P我们还需要用到过硼酸钠
To transform it into MD2P we need sodium perborate.
我们可以从水族箱专用盐里提取
We'll extract that from the integrators for aquariums.
我有一个非常巨大的水族箱
I've got a huge aquarium.
然后我们需要大量的蒸馏水，还需要糖霜做赋形剂
Then we need lots of distilled water, and icing sugar as an excipient.
第三步。生产。利用还原胺化反应
Phase 3. Production. Using reductive amination,
MD2P和丙氨酸可以为我们提供精神制剂
the MD2P and alanine will provide us with our smart drug.
到了这一步就无路可退，我们从现在起就在同一条船上了
The point of no return, we're all involved from here on.
好吧，彼得罗，对不起
All right, Pietro, I'm sorry.
就我而言，没戏了。跟其他人说再见吧
As far as I'm concerned, it's over. Say goodbye to the others.
- 现在怎么办，阿尔贝托？   - 你问我现在怎么办？
- What is it now, Alberto ?   - You're asking me what it is ?
你建议用硼氢化钠来进行还原胺化反应
You're suggesting sodium borohydride for reductive amination,
这么低级的事随便哪个吸毒的都会...
which is something so amateur any street junkie could do it...
- 哪有那么低级？   - 彼得罗，咱们实话实说
- It's not that amateur.   - Pietro, let's be honest.
要是你早讲用硼氢化钠来造毒品，我根本不会答应
If you'd said let's make a drug with sodium borohydride, I'd have said no.
- 嘘，中国人   - 我们是不是想造出像点样的毒品
- Sssh, the Chinese.   - Do we want to make a good drug,
合成达到一定级别的精神类药品？
synthesizing psychotropic substances of a certain level ?
达不到一定的纯度级别我们就不能干！
We can't go below a certain purity level !
不然的话，那种品相没人会喜欢的！
Otherwise it'll look bad and I won't have that !
好吧！好吧，算了！我们就用氢和铑
All right ! All right, come on ! We'll use hydrogen and rhodium.
- 满意了？   - 可以！可以！
- Happy ?   - Yes ! Yes!
不过，阿尔贝托，你真够讨厌的！
But, Alberto, what a pain !
我们要利用大学试验室
We'll use the university lab.
需要几个小时。我们周五晚上去，基本没人
We'll need a few hours, we'll go in on Friday night, when it's empty.
- 只是一道门，爬上翻过去   - 这没用
- It's only one gate, climb it backwards.   - That's not helping.
好吧。别慌。抓住把手
All right. Don't panic. Take the handle,
接着逆时针旋转180°，然后到我这边来
then an anticlockwise movement for 180 degrees and come towards me.
我应该下去再来一次
I should go back down and start again.
我们已经来了半个小时了。快点，监控会发现我们的
We've been here half an hour. Hurry up, the security camera will see us.
- 往左？   - 往左，来吧。不难，来
- Left ?   - Left, go. It's easy, go.
阿尔贝托！你说你虽然很胖但也很灵巧，可你就是个木墩子！
Alberto ! You said you were solid but agile, you're an armchair!
- 把手给我   - 我的手？   - 对，伸过来
- Give me your hand.   - My hand ? - Yes, give me it.
- 我就交给你了   - 手给我，快点
- I'm trusting you.   - Give me your hand. Come.
- 我撑不住了   - 什么？谁能拉得动你？
- I'll let go.   - What ? Who could hold you ?
下去重来吧。这是唯一的。。。
Go down and come back up. It's the only...
阿尔贝托！
Alberto !
- 我真想念这地方   - 嗯，快点
- I really missed this place.   - Yeah, come on.
除去赋形剂外，达到99%的纯度！
99% pure, apart from the excipients !
你不会怪我省了几个零的
You'll forgive me if I'm a few zeroes out.
你得使用高效液相色谱才能知道具体的纯度级别
To see certain levels of purity, you need HPLC.
是啊，阿尔贝托！两小时后这地方就全是人了！
Yes, Alberto ! In two hours this place will be full of people !
我们必须抓紧时间
We have to get a move on.
对，可这只是个整数，不能用来出售
Yes, but this is the zero number, this is not for sale.
不，我拿一个放我钱包里，行吗？
No, I'll take this one and put it in my wallet, OK ?
- 没问题   - 别担心了，但是动作要快！
- All right.   - So don't worry, but hurry up !
听着，我们要把整套试验做全吗？
Listen, are we going to do the whole testing phase ?
- 对，当然做全   - 是吗？
- Yes, of course we will.   - We will ?
你把这叫做科学试验？
You call this scientific testing ?
当然！不过我们就在这里做，而不是在试验室！
Of course ! But instead of doing it in the lab, we do it right here !
可在这种乱七八糟的环境里我们怎么收集试验证据？
How can we collect empirical evidence in this chaos ?
这环境根本就不适合，甚至起反作用
It's not a suitable environment, it's hostile even.
那些家伙从没来过夜总会
And these guys have never been in a club.
这就是我们需要一位人类学家的原因
That's why we got an anthropologist.
好的，最后一次。在夜总会里，肢体语言很重要
Right, for the last time. In a club, body language is fundamental.
如果你把胳膊指向出口处...把你的脚伸直！
If your arms are pointing to the exit... Straighten your feet !
就意味着我们有了负罪感，等不及要走了。那可不好！
It means we feel guilty and can't wait to go. That's no good !
高昂的下颔意味着自信
The raised chain is synonymous with self-assurance,
而且以人类学角度而言非常适合吸引那些
and is anthropologically perfect to attract everyone in here
想要离经叛道一晚的人
who wants to have a night off from ordinary morals.
所以把下颔抬高，绝对不要往那个方向看
So raised chin, never looking in that direction.
从少量的自我推销开始介绍我们自己
Start with a little self-marketing to introduce ourselves.
棒级了！
Great !
直到他们来找我们
Until it's them who come to us.
你有我需要的东西？
You got something for me ?
光有他们的需求是不够的，必须要他们渴求
It's not enough for them to want it, they have to desire it.
- 去别的地方走走！   - 别担心，我有钱！
- Go for a walk!   - Don't worry, I've got money !
到洗手间去看看
Go and check the restroom.
- 洗手间？   - 洗手间，去吧
- The restroom ?   - The restroom, go.
在洗手间里，关系会发生改变
In the restroom, relationships change,
大家会变得更融洽，即使是跟陌生人
people become more complicit even with strangers.
卫生间区域以性别划分
The toilet area discriminates on a gender basis,
男性在那边，女性在那边
males there, females there,
性别间的压力会消除
and so sexual tensions are smoothed out.
- 有人告诉我来这儿可以...   - 200欧元
- I was told to come here for...   - 200 euros.
- 200欧元，这是他妈什么玩意？   - 真有劲，谢谢
- 200 euros, what the hell is it ?   - A bomb, thank you.
- 我怎么跟你说的？   - 至少让我看一眼？
- What did I tell you ?   - Can I see it, at least ?
先给钱
Money first.
拿去！不过要是你敢耍我...
Here ! But if you rip me off...
- 敲最后那扇门。相信我   - 好吧
- Knock at the last door. Trust me.   - All right.
- 这系统不错！干得漂亮。再见   - 再见，帅哥
- What a system ! Well done. Bye.   - Bye, handsome.
瞧，我怎么跟你说的？
Look. What did I tell you ?
抱歉
Excuse me.
你好
Hello.
我是洗手间精神药品销售团队的
I'm part of the psychotropic sales team in the restroom.
- 我想知道你用了有什么感觉   - 这玩意挺酷的
- I wanted to ask what you thought.   - This stuff is spectacular.
能说具体一点吗？
Could you be more specific ?
当我过去敲卫生间的门时，我觉得这套系统很不错
When I went to knock on the restroom door, I saw the system is perfect.
- 跟穆雷纳学得有模有样   - 谁？
- Well clone, Murena.   - Who ?
穆雷纳。手里有顶级货的家伙。你不是替穆雷纳干活的？
Murena. The guy with the best stuff. Do you not work for Murena ?
我不认识穆雷纳。我替彼得罗干活
I don't know Murena. I work for Pietro.
要是按你的满意度打个分，按照...
If you were to grade your satisfaction on a scale of...
那妞是你带来的？
Is that your woman there ?
不，不是。你能集中一小会吗？
No, she's not. Can you concentrate a moment ?
嗯，我想我要去试试运气
Well, I think I'll try my luck.
抱歉！一小会，就一个问题！
Excuse me ! One moment, a question !
40分钟，各位，我们40分钟就搞定了！
40 minutes, guys, we finished it in 40 minutes !
不可思议！现在还不足以调整价格，我们得多生产一些
Amazing ! It's not enough to adjust the price, we have to make more.
好的，不过我想提一下分工的问题
All right, but I'd like to bring up the division of labor.
我发现有歧视、幽闭
I found it discriminatory, claustrophobic
尤其是卫生问题：
and above all unhygienic:
我坐在马桶上面整整两个小时
I was two hours sitting above the toilet bowl,
从门底下塞纸袋！
passing bags under the door !
乔吉奥，你的角色非常重要，看出来了？
Giorgio, your role is fundamental, you see ?
卫生间是底牌。万一警察来了
The WC is the estrema ratio. If the police come,
你把药丢进马桶，拿水一冲，我们干干净净走人！
you chuck it in the bowl, flush it away, and we're home free !
可我们不是说过这些都是合法的吗？
But did we not say all this was legal ?
说了一百遍了，我们出售的东西本身不是违法的
For the hundredth time, what we're selling in itself is not illegal,
但我们却在没有许可的情况下贩卖内服药品
but we're selling something that is ingested without any license,
而且没有处方，所以这是逃税行为！
and without receipts, so it's tax avoidance !
还有，阿尔贝托，别去打扰那些客户
And, Alberto, leave the customers in peace.
他们不是喜欢这药吗？这就够了
They like it ? That means it's good.
树皮被浸透后就会放入火中以营造温暖和温馨的气氛
ONCE SOAKED THE BARK IS PLACED ON THE FIRE TO MAKE IT WARM AND SOFT
听着，我一直在想，咱们弄台洗碗机吧
Listen, I was thinking, let's get the dishwasher.
你说了别太贪心
You said not to be too greedy.
没错，不过这个很有用的。我们就贪心一下
Yeah, but it's something useful. Let's be greedy.
不过买台酷的
But get a cool one.
- 你去哪？   - 去看看乔吉奥和马蒂亚
- Where are you going ?   - To see Giorgio and Mattia.
又来了！这周第三次了！
Again ! That's the third time this week !
可能是最后一次
And it might be the last.
他们现在有被开除的风险！
They're at risk of being fired !
我过去，聊聊天，想给他们打打气
I go there, chat, try to cheer them up a bit.
确实有用。其实他们也说了：“这对我们很有用”
It really helps them. In fact they said, "It really helps us."
那是新夹克吗？丝质的？
Is that a new jacket ? Is it silk ?
不是，睛纶混纺的。捂我一身汗
No, it's an acrylic mix. Really makes me sweat.
- 要不要我等你？   - 不用，亲爱的，睡吧。我很晚才能回来
- Will I wait up for you ?   - No, love, sleep, I'll be late.
我真得不想去！
I really don't want to go !
它的名字叫波希米亚狂想曲
And then we have Bohemian Rhapsody.
一条非常独特的狗，可以搜寻、捕猎、带回猎物
An exceptional dog, it seeks, hunts, retrieves.
- 你究竟想要哪种？   - 我们就要它了
- What exactly are you looking for ?   - We'll take it.
我们来了。这里是南罗马和托里诺的收入。瞧瞧
Here we are. This is South Rome and Torrino. Look at that.
- 等等，安德里亚，这是什么？   - 五欧元的钞票
- Hang on, Andrea, what's this ?   - Five euros.
我们不能收小面额的！我们不能整晚坐在这里数钱！
We don't take small notes ! We can't be here all night counting !
可以小小变通一下嘛
A bit of flexibility.
手里有小零钱的人不应该是我们的客户
If they have small change, they're not our clientele.
各位，我们将要去参观一些典雅的人文景观！
Guys, we're about to go somewhere anthropologically delicate !
很容易就能打动他们！别让我难堪
It won't take much to set things off ! Don't make me look bad.
要是有人感兴趣的话，这就是文书院宫
If anyone's interested, this is Palazzo della Cancelleria.
不是每个人都知道它有着达马西称号
Not everyone knows it contains the Titulus Damasi,
- 一般叫它圣洛伦索   - 够了！够了！
- commonly known as San Lorenzo.   - Enough ! Enough !
- 这裤子让我血脉不畅！   - 这种二分款真美
- These pants are haemostatic !   - The distichous is beautiful,
- 专为达玛苏...   - 我脱不下来了！
- dedicated to Damasus...   - I can't get them off!
不是所有人都知道她把教堂。。。算了，你们也不在意，我知道
Haec damasus tibi christe deus, all right, you don't care, I know.
我男朋友是天蝎座，有非常强烈的统治欲
My boyfriend is a Scorpio, very strong dominating character,
天蝎座运势，一个天蝎座大块头，真正的天蝎座！
Scorpio ascendant, a big Scorpio, really Scorpio !
我们也没必要搞得那么夸张！听着！
Just as well as we didn't have to overdo it ! Listen !
- 要货吗？   - 要，能让我晚上嗨起来
- You need some stuff ?   - Yeah, that would make my night.
- 900欧元   - 900欧元
- 900.   - 900.
讲真，各位，就和以前的生活方式一样，明白吗？
I mean it, guys, exactly the same lifestyle as before, understood ?
嗨。你能看得出来，我跟你一样是同性恋
Hi. As you can see, I'm a homosexual like you.
我就是想问问你刚才服的药
I wanted to ask about that substance you just took,
不过别担心，不记名的，只是用来研究...你干什么？
but don't worry, it's anonymous, it's research... What are you doing ?
好，谢谢你。不，我是想问你
Yes, thank you. No, I wanted to ask you,
比如，你对我无法扼制的性冲动
for example, that sexual impulse towards me you cannot control,
是不是依赖你刚才服的药？或者仅仅是因为你喜欢我？
does that depend on what you took ? Or is it just you like me ?
好吧，没关系。得了，住手！别！
All right, it doesn't matter. Come on, stop it ! No !
- 彼得罗   - 这他妈是什么？
- Pietro.   - What the fuck is this ?
- 洗碗机   - 我知道，可是...
- The dishwasher.   - I know, but...
- 你刚到家吗？   - 不是，我刚才...
- Have you just got home ?   - No, I was just...
- 我正要去大学   - 你那是皮裤吗？
- I was going to university.   - Are those leather pants ?
什么？不...挺舒适的，我买的特价
Who ? No... they're really comfy and I got them in the sales.
你要在早上六点上班？
You're going to work at 6 in the morning ?
教授要我给他帮个忙，因为我们经常这样，朱莉亚
The professor asked me for a favor, because we're like this, Giulia.
你至少把早饭吃了吗？
Have you had breakfast at least ?
我是说，虽然，彼得罗，要我说，你表现得怪怪的
I mean, though, Pietro, let me say, you're acting a bit strange.
看你这身打扮，就跟吉姆·莫里森一样（摇滚歌星）
Look at the way you're dressed, you look like Jim Morrison.
还有就是每天晚上去乔吉奥和马蒂亚那
And then this thing about going to see Giorgio and Mattia every night.
我理解你对于他们在加油站打工
I know you feel guilty they're pumping gas
而你却拿到了大学长期合同而过意不去...
and you've got a long-term contract at university...
- 彼得罗！你在听吗？   - 加油...
- Pietro ! Are you listening ?   - Pumping gas...
没什么，我在听，朱莉亚。不过我们总是
No, I was listening, Giulia. But we always talk
谈这些相同的话题。乔吉奥、马蒂亚、大学...
about the same things. Giorgio, Mattia, university...
一般人都要睡着了
It's normal for someone to fall asleep.
你从来不跟我讲你自己，你的情况。来，说说吧？
You never talk to me about you, how you are. There, how are you ?
工作上一团糟
Work's a real disaster.
吸毒的人数再次猛增
There's been a big rise in people taking drugs again.
一些新型药品正在流行...
There are these new pills going round...
...很多人再次回到吸毒的路上
...so many people have started using again.
而且这些药物似乎不算是违禁品
And it seems this thing's not officially illegal.
所以目前他们毫无办法。这些家伙肆无忌惮
So they can't do anything for now. These people are so unscrupulous,
我真想跳过审讯直接把他们关起来，终身监禁，这些杂种！
I'd lock them up without even a trial, life in jail, these shits !
喂，“杂种”这词有点过了
Well, "shits" seems a bit over the top,
也许他们遇到了困难，要申请取缔非常容易
maybe they've had problems, and it's too easy to demand a clampdown.
彼得罗，你到底在说什么？
Pietro, what the fuck are you saying ?
他们弄出近几年最好的毒品之一，你却在为他们辩解？
They put one of the best drugs in years out there and you defend them ?
不...但是是谁这么说，说这些药品非常酷？
No... but who said that, that these pills are cool ?
那些曾经尝试过的人！还有谁？
The people that have tried them ! Who else ?
他们怎么说的？这些药是，比方说，一般酷或是真心酷，酷？
What did they say ? Are they, like, normal cool or really cool, cool ?
- 你疯了吗？   - 没有，只是聊一聊
- Are you insane ?   - No, it was just to have a chat.
你说我们从没聊过天
You say we never talk.
你不饿吗？不喜欢？要不要点别的东西？
Are you not hungry ? You not like it ? You want something else ?
先生，菜单上说这是50欧元一盘！
Sir, it says here this is 50 euros a plate !
我跟你们说过。我们的津贴往上涨了...我来付帐
I told you. They increased our allowances... I'll get it.
想想第二道菜，光鱼类就有三页
Think about a second course, there's three pages of fish alone.
随您怎么讲，先生
If you say so, sir.
我对什么人办什么事
I deal stuff of a certain level for people of a certain level.
我组织的派对，快乐大本营，是为了让大家高兴
The parties I organize, Happiness, are to entertain people,
- 让他们留下回忆并感激我   - 当然
- so they remember and are grateful.   - Of course.
我们说的是每晚2万多欧元
We're talking 20,000 a night plus.
我在罗马经常用到这位穆雷纳。我不知道你是否认识他
In Rome I've always used this Murena. I don't know if you know him.
知道，我听说过这位穆雷纳
Yes, I've heard something about this Murena.
不过我可以保证我们有当前市场上最好的产品
But I can guarantee we have the best product on the market at the moment.
好吧，你可以收下我漂亮的名片，放进你的口袋
All right, you take my nice business card, put it in your pocket,
给我发条普通短信，我们下次见面谈谈细节
send me a neutral text message and we'll meet to discuss the details.
这是150平米的休息厅，是真正的珠宝
This is the lounge and with its 150 square meters it's a real jewel.
正如你所见，这露台有着极佳的罗马市区视角
As you can see, the terrace offers an unrivaled view of downtown Rome,
上层露台有温水泳池，桑拿和一个小健身房
while the upper terrace has a heated pool, sauna and a small gym.
你们想待多久？
How long were you thinking of staying ?
我们想的是长期方面
We were thinking more of an open-ended thing.
- 这根是承重柱吗？   - 您说什么？
- Is this a bearing pillar ?   - Pardon ?
也许该把它敲掉，感觉有点挡事
To knock it down maybe, it's all a bit claustrophobic.
这里是旅馆，你不能做出改动
This is a hotel, you can't rebuild it.
我们的想法只不过是来自后工业化的现代开放空间
It's just we come from a post-industrial modern open space.
不管怎么说，我们要了
But anyway we'll take it.
好了，阿尔贝托，继续
On you go, Alberto, go on.
这只是一次科学试验
It's just a scientific experiment.
你已经做了很多次了，不是吗？
You've done lots, haven't you ?
勇敢点，勇敢点，勇敢点
Be brave, be brave, be brave.
你们抢生意抢到这儿来了？
You're breaking our balls here too ?
滚一边去！你想干嘛？
Fuck off! What do you want ?
- 他还敢还嘴！   - 哥们，这儿是穆雷纳的地盘
- He answers back as well !   - Buddy, Murena's in charge here.
“哥们，这儿是穆雷纳的地盘”。你看太多美剧了
"Buddy, Murena's in charge here." You watch too many American movies...
该死，老天，你把我鼻子打破了！你疯了吗？
Fuck, Christ, you've broken my nose ! Are you mad ?
在托里诺搞一点就搞一点了，我们也不小气
Pushing a bit out at Torrino was OK, we let you do that,
可你们现在在挑逗我们的神经
but now you're pissing us off.
下次再让我们看见你们，我们就开枪了，明白吗？
Next time we see you, we'll shoot you. Understand ?
- 没那个必要   - 这里是穆雷纳的地盘儿，懂？
- There was no need for that.   - This is Murena's patch, OK ?
不，各位，你们真地对美剧太入迷了...
No, guys, you're really obsessed with these American movies...
- 刚才是谁，巴尔托洛梅奥？   - 穆雷纳。穆雷纳的人
- Who was it, Bartolomeo ?   - Murena. Murena's men.
该死的穆雷纳！该死的穆雷纳！
Fucking Murena ! Fucking Murena !
我总是听到他的名字，穆雷纳，你把我惹毛了！
I keep hearing his name, Murena, you've broken my balls !
- 这些是不折不扣的坏蛋   - 你不懂，巴尔托洛梅奥
- These are real bad guys.   - You don't understand, Bartolomeo.
- 我们现在才是坏蛋   - 我们得把他们搞定！
- We're the bad guys now.   - We need to screw them !
我们得找点称手的家伙把他们脸打扁！
We'll get some cold weapons and smash their faces in !
你干了什么？
What have you done ?
你不让我测试它们，所以我对自己说，试一下
You didn't let me test them, so I said to myself, try it.
喝点水，保持体内水份
Drink some water and stay hydrated.
- 彼得罗，我们该怎么办？   - 跟你们说，我们必须把他们搞定
- Pietro, what will we do ?   - I'm telling you, we have to screw them up .
这东西挺黏，我们得解决发干的问题。记下来
This stuff's sticky, we need to sort out the dryness. Take a note.
各位，我们得改变一下思路
Guys, we need to really change mentality.
我们不能总是去厕所，穿得像傻逼，挣点零花钱
We can't keep going to squats, dressed like fools, for loose change.
我们得上个台阶
We have to go up a level.
- 你们有晚礼服吗？   - 有！不行，不太合身！
- Have you got a tux ?   - Yes ! No, it doesn't fit !
记下来！改晚礼服
Take a note ! Adjust tux.
喂！太好了！你不知道看见你来我有多高兴
Hey ! Great ! You don't know how happy I am that you're here.
- 感谢您邀请我们   - 我们开始尽情享受这个夜晚吧
- Thank you for inviting us.   - Let's enjoy the evening now.
西蒙，你能去那边看着点吗？我来带你认识一下大家
Simon, will you deal with the giving and getting ? I'll introduce you.
你好...我是阿尔贝托
Hello... I'm Alberto.
我是红辣椒
Paprika.
红辣椒。这名字不一般
Paprika. Unusual.
抱歉离开一会。我马上回来。你不要离开
Excuse me a moment. I'll be right back. Don't you go anywhere.
以第三方名义办理的巴拿马手机卡，烧了吧
Forget it, really. Panamanian SIM card in a third party's name.
他们全都能截听到，共谋罪够判9年的
They'll be on to you, and I was looking at nine years for conspiracy.
不过，如果你想图个安稳，那记下来，“Palabras”！
No, these days not to have any worries, write it down, Palabras !
- “Palabras”？   - 玻利维亚第二大公司。很好的
- Palabras ?   - Second company in Bolivia. Great.
- 感觉可靠吗？   - 可靠？
- In the sense it's secure ?   - Secure ?
要是法官截听到了，我怎么说？
If the judge manages to tap this, what can I say ?
你不错，真不错。我会去自首。不过他不会截听到的
You're good, really good. I'll hand myself in. But he won't tap it.
只要有我的，就会有你们的
Since I got one, everyone's got one.
- 抱歉   - 你随意
- Excuse me.   - On you go.
亲爱的！不，我们和部长们在一起。他们希望明天颁布法令
Love ! No, we're with the ministers. They want the decree for tomorrow.
- 彼得罗！   - 教授
- Pietro !   - Professor.
很高兴见到你！你在这儿做什么？你消失一阵子了！
It's good to see you ! What are you doing here ? You vanished !
我一直在尽最大努力让你回来！
I'm doing all I can to get you back in !
我甚至去见了学校出去的一位老朋友，很有人脉的家伙
I even went to see an old friend from school, a guy with contacts.
教授，谢谢你，不过我已经没有兴趣了，我改行了
Professor, thank you, but I'm not interested, I've changed fields.
你干得不错，你在大学里挣不到什么
You did well, you can't earn a fucking thing at university.
抱歉，不过你刚才在跟帕拉佐副部长说话
Excuse me, but you were speaking with Undersecretary Pallazzo.
对，别人介绍的。。。
Yes, I was introduced...
他和我的船停在同一个码头
He and I have our boats at the same pier,
可我从没有勇气接近他
but I've never been bold enough to approach him.
不过要是你能在他面前帮我牵个线
But if you could maybe have a word with him about me,
至少让我加入国家研究委员会
get me a seat on the board of the NRC at least.
- 我不知道，教授...   - 去代表民间团体
- I don't know, Professor...   - To represent civil society.
- 抱歉，我真得要走了   - 等一等
- I'm sorry, I really have to go.   - Hang on.
这是我的名片。我不得不换号了，萨勒诺地方检察官一直在找我麻烦
Take my card. I had to change numbers, the Salerno D.A. was hassling me.
- 谢谢   - 看到+591的号码别见怪
- Thank you.   - Don't worry about the +591,
是玻利维亚号码，说来话长了，以后我会告诉你的
it's a Bolivian number, it's a long story, I'll tell you later.
拉力赛能带给你的冲击不是其它运动可比的
Rallying gives you a rush that no other sport does.
- 可是却有副作用！   - 那你现在级别挺高的了？
- But then there are side effects !   - So you're at a certain level ?
我参加了最近的一次非洲艾克拉力赛，尽管有个垃圾导航
I was placed in the last Africa Eco Race despite an asshole navigator.
在沙丘上，要是你没个好导航，你就完蛋了！
And on the dunes, if you don't have a good navigator, you're screwed !
我找了你将近半小时
I've been looking for you for half an hour.
- 你能给我一点货吗？   - 干嘛？
- Can you give me some stuff ?   - What for ?
做测试。我会把结果发给你。拿来！
The tests. I'll send you the file. Give !
阿尔贝托，你知道定期服用会上瘾的
Alberto, you know regular ingestion can lead to addiction.
别逗我了！把药给我！
Don't break my balls ! Give me the pills!
悠着点！
Behave!
- 快点！   -等等！
- Come on !   - Wait !
可又不是我！我为什么要说谎？
But that's not me ! Why would I lie ?
得了，我知道是你！
Stop it, I know it's you !
其实，我还认识你们帮派另一个家伙
In fact, I know that guy there is one of your gang too.
什么帮派？哪有帮派。像他那种人会是帮派里的？不可能...
What gang ? There's no gang. Someone like him in a gang ? No way...
- 我认识你们所有人，都认识！   - 这事和我无关
- I know all of you, I know !   - It's nothing to do with me.
不管怎么说我都不明白...
I don't understand though in what sense...
啊，你说的是字面意思？
Ah, you mean literally ?
当然，如果你这样想...
Of course, if you put it like that...
是我
It's me.
可是...
But...
- 阿尔贝托，你在这做什么？   - 吃早餐
- Alberto, what are you doing here ?   - Having breakfast.
我晚上有点累
I had a bit of a night.
阿尔贝托，这两位是不是保镖？
Alberto, do you think these two are escorts ?
我想搞清楚，可她只用俄语回答
I tried to bring that up, but she only answered in Russian,
但是，不，我想不是的
but no, I don't think so.
阿尔贝托，她们是保镖
Alberto, they're escorts.
你觉得那种女孩会看上我们这样的人吗？
You think girls like that would go with the likes of us ?
那是你的看法！我就有更漂亮的女孩看上
Speak for yourself ! I've had better-looking girls.
- 谁？   - 维罗尼卡，博士学位，第二年
- Who ?   - Veronica, doctorate, second year.
我觉得我们得给她们1000欧元
I think we'll need to give them 1,000 euros.
算是出于礼貌
Just out of politeness.
- 你去哪了？已经下午2点了！   - 在大学
- Where were you ? It's 2pm !   - At university.
- 看你满身酒气！   - 我们在用乙醇，所以。。。
- You stink of alcohol !   - We're using ethanol and so...
- 你身上穿着礼服去工作？   - 好啦，朱莉亚，听着
- You go to work in a tux ?   - Come on, Giulia, please,
昨天是我们一个同事的单身汉告别晚会，我们都穿着礼服。。。
it was a stag night for a colleague and we all dressed up in tuxes...
单身汉告别晚会？谁的？哪位同事？
A stag night ? Whose ? What colleague ?
你认识的。。。詹。。。卢卡。。。奇拉。。。
You know... Gian...luca... Ciarra...
瓦那利。詹卢卡·奇拉瓦那利博士
vanellini. Doctor Gianluca Ciarravanellini.
你是不是觉得我很好骗？我们怎么能买得起这些玩意？
Do you think I'm stupid ? How the fuck did we buy all these things ?
3D电视，洗碗机，所有这些该死的外套，你差不多买了300件！
The 3D TV, the dishwasher, all these fucking jackets, you've got 300 of them !
朱莉亚，冷静。我告诉过你的，这都来自2008年起的拨款。。。
Giulia, calm down. I told you, it's a grant from 2008...
我去了大学。他们说已经有几个月没见过你了！
I went to the university. They say they haven't seen you for months !
至于什么长期合同。。。
As for the long term-contract...
第一，别用手指我。第二，别过问我的事
One, don't lift your hands to me. Two, keep your nose out my business.
第三，我本来想告诉你的，我已经有了新的工作
Three, I was going to tell you, I've got a new job.
是吗？种种迹象来看是份高收入的工作！
Yeah ? A well-paid one by the look of things !
- 你从哪拿出来的？   - 你藏在哪就是哪！
- Where did you get this ?   - Where you hid it !
这些该死的钱哪来的？
Where the fuck is this money from ?
这是我跟乔吉奥和马蒂亚一起干的，一项投资。。。
It's something I'm doing with Giorgio and Mattia, an investment...
- 这该死的钱是从哪里来的？   - 你想知道？是吗？该死！
- Where the fuck is this money from ?   - You wanna know ? You do ? Fuck !
我现在是个毒贩！满意了？
I've become a dealer ! All right ?
- 滚你的吧！   - 不，是你滚！
- Fuck off !   - No, you fuck off !
我被大学开掉了！明白吗？我被开掉了！
I got kicked out the university ! Understand ? I got kicked out !
我不知道该怎么办，除了分子理论我一无所长
I don't know how to do anything, all I can do is theorize molecules,
所以我推理出一种能带给我回报的分子结构！
so I theorized one that gives me what I deserve !
这个白痴竟然开始贩毒！而我还以为他有了个新欢！
This dickhead's started dealing ! And I thought he had a lover !
- 新欢？别跑题   - 这个白痴！
- A lover ? Don't change the subject.   - This dickhead !
- 我上班后该怎么讲？   - 朱莉亚，听着，我所做的一切都是为了我们
- What will I say at work ?   - Giulia, listen, I did it for us,
能享受体面的生活，别把它彻底毁了
to have a decent life, don't blow it out of all proportion.
我会攒些钱然后随时可以退出
I'll save some money then I can quit anytime I like.
我该怎么跟我的孩子讲？
What do I tell my child ?
爸爸在牢里，别把它彻底毁了！
Dad's in jail, don't blow it out of all proportion !
朱莉亚，你紧张的时候就会乱说一气。监牢和我有什么。。。
Giulia, when you're stressed you talk shit. What's jail got to do...
什么孩子？
What child ?
彼得罗，我怀孕了
Pietro, I'm pregnant.
你怀孕了？
You're pregnant ?
抱歉，你到底打算什么时候才告诉我？
I'm sorry, when the fuck were you going to tell me ?
你能肯定吗？
You're sure ?
不是臆想型怀孕？
It's not a hysterical pregnancy ?
滚蛋
Get out.
- 彼得罗！很高兴你在这儿   - 朱莉亚把我赶出来了
- Pietro ! I'm glad you're here.   - Giulia's kicked me out,
我得找个地方待几晚
I need somewhere to stay a couple of nights.
巴尔托洛梅奥出了点状况。从辛蒂来了两位男士
There's a problem with Bartolomeo. There are two Sinti gentlemen here,
态度不怎么友好，我不想和他们有瓜葛
not at all friendly, I don't want anything to do with this.
辛蒂？
Sinti ?
别碰我！我自己能走，没必要使用暴力。。。
Don't touch me ! I can come myself, there's no need for violence...
彼得罗，别问为什么，很明显是用辞方面理解有误
Pietro, don't ask, obviously a linguistic misunderstanding,
他们说什么婚姻，我一点都不知道
they're talking about a marriage I know nothing about.
别碰我，我在走。我自己能走。。。
Don't touch me, I'm coming. I can come on my own...
你知道的，这个模型不是用的伊特鲁里亚语，而是大希腊区语
As you know, the matrix isn't Etruscan, but Magna Graecia.
显然客户是伊特鲁里亚人
The client was Etruscan, obviously.
我知道，抱歉，但不幸的是我们找不到更好的地方了
I know, I'm sorry, but unfortunately we couldn't find anything better.
我早就想找个更大点的地方，这里有点挤
I'm already looking for something bigger, this is a bit cramped,
没地方能摆下台球桌，那电影院。。。
there's no room for the pool table, the movie theater...
- 马蒂亚，这些女孩子哪来的？   - 我不太清楚
- Mattia, who are all these girls ?   - I'm not really sure.
从语言学上讲，在泳池里说的是斯拉夫语，但进了屋更像拉美语
Linguistically at the pool it's Slav, but more Latin-American indoors.
姑娘们，那个不是烟灰缸！那是91年Certamen Ciceronianum大奖赛的奖杯！
Girls, that's not an ashtray ! It's the Certamen Ciceronianum Cup '91 !
抱歉，那是国际大赛。92年的已经被你弄丢了
Sorry, it's an international competition. You've already lost '92.
- 阿图罗，你在做什么？   - 穆洛的山墙装饰
- Arturo, what are you doing ?   - The acroterion of Murlo.
这太让人意外了。真正的晴天霹雳
It was so unexpected. It was a real bolt from the blue.
我觉得我已经做好了准备，你知道的，准备做个父亲
I feel I'm ready. You know, to be a father.
我觉得我很失败，我们在一起这么多年
I feel I'm cut out for it, we've been together for years,
有了爱情的结晶本来是多美妙啊
it would be a lovely thing to put the seal on our love.
- 你要不要口活？   - 什么意思，口活？
- You want a blow job ?   - What do you mean, a blow job ?
我说的是某种复杂的个人动力。。。
I'm talking about personal dynamics of a certain complexity...
- 不想要口活吗？   - 不，不要，算了！
- No blow job ?   - No, no blow job, come on !
不是针对个人。当作我接受了吧
Nothing personal. It's like I accepted.
这里有浴室吗？抱歉。口活
Is there a bathroom here ? I'm sorry. A blow job.
你就是个不负责任的杂碎。我讨厌这地方，滚吧！
YOU'RE AN IRRESPONSIBLE SHIT. I HATE THIS PLACE, FUCK OFF !
- 你开始人身攻击了！   - 你也给我滚
- You're really getting personal !   - YOU FUCK OFF AS WELL.
她嫌这个地方太乱了，她想要个只属于我们的地方
All this chaos gets to her, she'd like a place just for us.
她说得对，这地方已经失去控制了。钱改变了他们的思想
She's right, this lot up there have lost it, the money's changed them.
你有没有注意到这地方被妓女填满了？
Have you noticed this place is full of hookers ?
阿尔贝托，那不是那天晚上那个保镖吗？
Alberto, is that not the escort from the other night ?
不，红辣椒不再是保镖了。她现在为我们工作，负责公共关系
No, Paprika's not an escort any more. She works for us now, does our PR.
阿尔贝托，那东西省着点用。你服了多少？
Alberto, go easy with that stuff. How much are you taking ?
别担心！你没必要担心
Don't worry ! You mustn't worry.
这周我会把结果用文件发给你
I'll send you the file with the results this week.
- 阿尔贝托！   - 俄语的意思是“马上来”。酷！
- Alberto !   - It means coming in Russian. Cool !
我要走了，因为她要是生气的话，能把我吓到
I'm going, cos if she gets pissed, she frightens me a bit.
耶！这药不错，彼得罗。这药不错，你应该尝试一下
Yeah ! It's good, Pietro. It's good, you need to try it.
听话，试试，你应该试试
Be good, try it, you need to try it.
我知道我辜负了你的信任。我让你们失望了，你们所有人
I realize I betrayed your trust. I let you down, all of you.
相比1000天这还不到一星期。问题是这种新药，很猛
Less than a week from 1,000 days. The problem is this new stuff, it's wild.
我以前用过药。我又不是雏
I've taken pills before, I'm no virgin,
不过，各位，这让人难以置信，它似乎。。。
but, guys, this is just unbelievable, it's something...
我这辈子从没这么嗨过
I've never been so high in my life,
像是从你胸口喷涌而出的愉悦，一种。。。
it's like a jet of pleasure coming out your chest, a thing...
好了，卢卡，你搞得好像在为这药打广告一样。抱歉
All right, Luca, all that's missing is the testimonial. Excuse me.
有事。肯定的
Spatial. Definitive.
整整三天你都不接电话。让我进去，我们谈谈
You haven't answered the phone in 3 days. Let me in, let's talk.
彼得罗，你是个毒品贩子。你应该感谢我没去举报你
Pietro, you're a drug dealer. Be grateful I haven't reported you.
说了一百次了，我们这个配方在意大利不是违禁药
For the hundredth time, the molecule we produced is not illegal in Italy.
至少在政府清单下次更新前都不是的
Not till the Ministry's next update, at least.
而且我或许是名销售人员，别叫我贩子，我不喜欢！
And I'm a salesman maybe, don't call me a dealer, I don't like it!
朱得亚，朱莉亚。求你！对不起！好吗？
Giulia, Giulia. Please ! I'm sorry ! OK ?
我很抱歉，但是肯定有办法解决这件事，不是吗？
I'm sorry, but there must be a way to sort things out, no ?
你说你随时可以退出。那就退出啊！马上！
You said you can quit anytime you want. So quit! Now!
- 朱莉亚，这事有点复杂   - 这事复杂
- Giulia, it's complicated.   - It's complicated.
这事涉及到了孩子。所以我们必须得谈谈。这也是我的孩子！
There's a child involved. So we have to talk. It's my child as well !
你想谈谈？那就谈吧！继续！我听着呢，谈
You want to talk ? Talk, then ! Go on ! I'm listening, talk.
好吧，可是隔着围栏谈，还有。。。
All right, but talking with a fence between us, with...
一群吸毒鬼在看着，不，我谈不来
all the junkies watching, no, I can't.
晚餐吧，我就想要共进一次晚餐
One dinner, that's all I'm asking come to dinner one time.
- 天呐！这是什么玩意？   - 一瓶97年的特级Aspero
- Goodness ! What is this stuff ?   - A '97 Aspero Superiore,
- 非常罕见，400欧元一瓶   - 这是亚硫酸盐汁！
- very rare, 400 euros a bottle.   - It's sulfite juice !
你没弄到桑泰尔皮迪奥的Tenuta，德拉龙河？
You not got a Tenuta Sant'Elpidio, a De la Garonne ?
女士已经来了。我们一会再谈酒的事，这瓶不怎么样
The lady's here. We'll discuss the wine later, it's not good enough.
抱歉，那位先生已经包下了今晚的整场
I'm sorry, the gentleman has booked the whole place this evening.
这座位已经预订了，其实整座餐馆都预订了，所以，请。。。
This seat is taken, as indeed is the whole restaurant, so, please...
你真以为你可以不计后果地造成所有这些混乱吗？
You really thought you could cause all this chaos with no consequences ?
什么？
Pardon ?
你和你的屌丝朋友们突然冒出来
You and your loser friends appearing out of nowhere
在这为所欲为！我该不该生气？
and doing as you like ! Should I be pissed ?
要是该有人生气的话，应该是我。你只是。。。
If anyone should be pissed, it's me. You're a...
这他妈是什么？
What the fuck is this ?
要是由我来做决定的话，我早就一枪崩了你
If it was up to me I'd have shot you already.
但是市场说了算，而且你做的东西有需求
But the market is king, and there's a demand for what you make.
你是穆雷纳？
You're Murena ?
我是你的新雇主
I'm your new employer.
不，听着，我们不替任何人打工，我们自己干。。。
No, look, we don't work for anyone, we work for ourselves...
你还没明白
You don't get it.
后天
Day after tomorrow,
给我带10公斤那些你和你朋友们做出来的可爱药丸
bring me 10 kilos of those lovely pills you and your friends make,
然后我们再说
and then we'll see.
10公斤？两天内？你知道吗？我不干！
Ten kilos ? In two clays ? You know what ? I'm doing nothing !
你不知道我是谁！你不能就这么拿枪指着我然后。。。
You don't know who I am ! You can't just point your gun and...
你女朋友叫什么来着？
What's your girlfriend called ?
那个社会服务人员，是不是？好吧！
The social worker, isn't she ? All right !
- 该死！   - 朱莉亚？
- Fuck!   - Giulia ?
不，是阿尔贝托。彼得罗，出事了，别生气。。。
No, it's Alberto. Pietro, something's happened, don't be angry...
- 我的车失去了控制   - 车？什么车？
- I lost control of the coupe.   - The coupe ? What coupe ?
- 不，我没事   - 阿尔贝托，听着。。。
- No, I'm fine.   - Alberto, listen...
我是想把车控制住，但我刚跟红辣椒吵架了。。。
I was trying to get it out my system, I'd a fight with Paprika...
我没时间！我没时间
I don't have time ! I don't have time.
不，不，等等。我还有事
No, no, wait. I called for another reason.
当他们检查汽车时
When they checked the car,
在车里，他们发现了半公斤我们那种药。。。
inside, they found half a kilo of our pills...
- 你车上有什么？   - 我没想到他们会检查！
- What did you have ?   - I didn't think they'd look!
警察都很狡猾，他们非常聪明。我本来不认为。。。
The police are sneaky, they're clever. I didn't think so...
要是他们问你什么，闭好嘴巴，什么都别说。。。
If they ask anything, shut up, don't say...
马上把电话挂了。跟我们去警局
Hang up now. Follow us to the station.
阿尔贝托！
Alberto !
朱莉亚，你必须离开！我会来接你。。。
Giulia, you have to get away ! I'll come and get you...
朱莉亚！是她的名字。我把电话给她，我想她有点生气了
Giulia ! That's her name. I'll put her on, I think she's a bit pissed.
亲爱的，别担心，一切都在控制之中，你不会有事的
Love, don't worry, it's all under control, nothing will happen to you.
屁的控制！我已经被绑架了
Under fucking control ! I've been kidnapped.
绑架？不，谈判还在继续，明白吗？
Kidnap ? No, there are ongoing negotiations, understand ?
开的价太高了。。。
Things were said...
如果他们想要赎金，你绝不能给
If they ask for a ransom, don't you pay it.
钱不能给。因为我一旦给放了，我要做的第一件事。。。
Don't pay it. Because as soon as I'm free, the first thing I'll do
就是打扁你那张无耻的脸，明白吗？蠢货！
is break your shitty face, do you understand ? Dickhead !
好吧。我想我们算是意见一致了
All right. I think we've reached an agreement.
别碰她！你不知道我的能力。你不知道！
Don't touch her ! You don't know what I'm capable of. You don't know !
你能制做药丸。10公斤，后天
You're capable of making pills. 10 kilos, the day after tomorrow.
穆雷纳，别挂！听我说！穆雷纳！妈的！
Murena, don't hang up ! Listen to me ! Murena ! Fuck you !
妈的！
Fuck you !
好，佩里，帮我弄明白这里的事情
Right, Petrelli, help me understand something here.
交警说你当时在应急车道上时速超过了240公里
The traffic police say you were in the emergency lane doing 240km/h,
车是三天前以800欧元一天租的一辆银灰色4002轿车
in a metallic grey 4002 coupe, rented three days ago at 800 euros a day.
作为一个洗碗工，你的待遇很不错啊
For a dishwasher, you look after yourself.
接下来是后座上的八千欧元现金
Then on the rear seat there were 8,000 euros cash,
- 一根警棍和一支瓦斯手枪   - 自卫用的
- a night stick and a gas pistol.   - For self-defense.
但是真正让我感兴趣的是这袋子里装的半公斤药丸
But what interests me is this bag we found with half a kilo of pills
现在正在试验室里检验，不过我倒是想猜猜看那是什么
which are being tested at the lab, but I'd take a guess at what it is.
但是不管怎么说那是一个完全合法的配方
But anyway it's a perfectly legal molecule.
- 谁这样说？   - 政府部门有个清单。。。
- Says who ?   - The Ministry has a list...
- 这些东西你是怎么知道的？   - 卫生部的网站上有
- How do you know all this ?   - It's on the Health Ministry site.
- 我可以在电脑上给你看一下   - 你想耍我吗？
- I'll show you on the computer.   - You trying to piss me off ?
我们非常清楚你放在车里的药
We know the drug you had in the car really well.
你加入了那个研究员帮派？脑子坏了吗？
You're in the researchers' gang ? What's wrong ?
你们以为我们什么都不知道，你们能够为所欲为？
You thought we didn't know anything, that you could what you liked ?
关于精神药剂你想不想说点什么？
You wanna have a talk about smart drugs ?
科勒蒂，是谁负责告诉政府关于新药剂的出现？
Coletti, who tells the Ministry about the new substances ?
是我们，就从这间办公室，探长
We do, from this office, Inspector.
所以说你来对地方了，阿尔贝托！
So you're in the right place, Alberto !
但我什么都不知道
But I don't know anything.
我只知道你不能这样抓我，我有权见律师！
All I know is you can't hold me like this, I have the right to a lawyer !
好了，好了，我们面前就有一个
All right, all right, you've got one over us for now.
我不知道你是从哪弄到的这个配方，但是你知道
I don't know where you got this molecule from, but you did,
现在这个配方变成非法的只是个时间问题
and now it's only a question of time until the molecule becomes illegal.
其他人是谁，阿尔贝托？
Who are the others, Alberto ?
别在这瞎扯了！停！
Stop it with this bullshit ! Stop it !
我们去找个律师把他弄出来。我们不清楚警察手里有什么
We'll get a lawyer and get him out. We don't know what the cops have.
你没在听。阿尔贝托跟红辣椒说过，他们全都知道了。有什么好笑的？
You're not listening. Alberto has been speaking to Paprika, they know everything. What's so funny ?
但为什么是红辣椒？现在问题出在红辣椒身上。她的可靠度。。。
But why Paprika ? The problem's Paprika now. Her reliability...
你们能不能认真听一下？我们必须干一件事
Will you listen for a moment ? We have to do one thing.
做最后一单，然后我们解散帮派分散开来
Do the last deal, then we break up the gang and split up.
- 那阿尔贝托呢？   - 去他的阿尔贝托！
- And Alberto ?   - Fuck Alberto !
他是个喜欢飙车，整天与妓女为伴的吸毒鬼
He's a junkie who goes with hookers, crashing sports cars.
阿尔贝托会害我们全部进监狱的，懂吗！醒醒！
Alberto is going to send us all to jail, please ! Come on !
我们可以自首。考虑到减刑因素
We could give ourselves up. With the mitigating factors
我们能得到一个有利的判决
we might get a very favorable sentence.
抱歉，抱歉，一个问题
Excuse me, excuse me, one question.
我们在试着怎么把一个人弄出监狱
We're trying to work out how to get someone out of jail,
可你却想让大家都进监狱，你脑子进水了吗？
and you want us all to go to prison, what the fuck is wrong with you ?
这只是个建议
It was just a suggestion.
你知道我想不明白哪一点吗？你从什么时候开始有权力开口的？
You know what I don't get ? Since when did you have the right to speak ?
你就是靠你那辆卡车才能留在这。还记得吗？
You're only here cos you have a truck. You remember that ?
是那个做了金融计划的高级金融天才说的。。。
Said the genius of high finance with his financial plan...
是谁付的钱？谁把钱弄来让这个业务开动的？
Who paid up ? Who found the money to start this business ?
是谁用他的鼻血换来的钱？他们用暴力让我结婚！
Who paid with his nasal septum ? They want me to get married !
我愿不愿意是另外一回事，不过别再说废话了！
That I won't is another thing, but don't talk shit !
这真是太无礼了
This really is disrespectful.
彼得罗，我不想进监狱
Pietro, I don't want to go to jail.
谁都不会去监狱。我们再做最后一次
Nobody's going to jail. We do it one last time.
10公斤。1公斤10万，总共100万
Ten kilos. 100,000 a kilo. A million.
- 这100万卖给谁？   - 批发，给穆雷纳
- Who do we sell a million to ?   - Wholesale. To Murena.
- 谁？   - 穆雷纳
- Who ?   - Murena.
卖给穆雷纳？我打电话给他
To Murena ? I'll call him.
穆雷纳先生，我们见下面。。。我们提供10公斤给你，你给我们100万
Mr. Murena, let's meet at...we give you 10 kilos, you give us 1 million.
好了？他手里有枪，把我们干掉之后拿货走人。多棒的点子
All right ? He gets a gun, shoots us and takes the stuff. Great idea.
不，我们有更好的交易地点，那里的人比他要危险得多
No, we have a place for the deal with more dangerous people than him.
- 在哪？   - 你的婚礼
- Where ?   - Your wedding.
去你妈的！干嘛总盯着我？没看见我的脸成什么样了吗？
Fuck off ! Why is it always me ? Have you seen my face ?
- 什么意思？   - 无论如何都不行
- Why ?   - It can't be done anyway.
10公斤的药丸，上哪去找这么多丁香酚？去抢药店？
10 kilos of pills, where will be get the eugenol ? Robbing a pharmacy ?
我们要去抢药店？
We're robbing a pharmacy ?
- 怎么样？   - 做任何事都要有个限度
For example, there's a limit to everything.
为什么我们做的每件事都要这么离奇曲折？
Why does everything we do have to have a surreal twist ?
这玩意可以为我们的可靠度加多少分？
What is the temperature of our credibility with this stuff ?
你疯了吗？它们来自拿破仑的意大利战役
Are you mad ? These are from Napoleon's Italian campaign,
我们才把它们收进帝峰皇店的目录
we just catalogued them for the Hermitage.
它们来自曼图亚第二次攻防战，由Tunz将军指挥的！
These are from the second siege of Mantua, with General Tunz !
- 好吧，可是它们还能开火吗？   - 它们好用得很
- Yes, but do they shoot ?   - They work perfectly.
- 我们干嘛要开枪？   - 以防万一的
- Why do we have to shoot ?   - They're for if things go wrong.
什么意思，以防万一？
What does that mean, if things go wrong ?
我说的就是！以防万一！
What I said ! If things go wrong !
这样某些人就不会再唠叨我仅仅是因为有辆车才在这的
So someone will stop saying I'm only here for the truck.
各位，我是这里唯一一个自欺欺人的吗？
Guys, am I the only person here shitting himself ?
而且我们还有刺刀。要是用得上的话
And we also have bayonets. If we need.
- 举起手来，蠢货！   - 这是他妈什么玩意？
- Hands up, dickhead !   - What the fuck is this ?
手不要碰柜台，敢碰报警器我就开枪
Hands off the counter, don't hit the alarm or I'll shoot.
想死是吗？把该死的手拿开！
You wanna die ? Move your fucking hands !
这里没有报警器！我们不是在美国！
There is no alarm ! We're not in America !
他说得对，可怜的家伙，这里不是银行，是药店！
He's right, poor thing, it's not a bank, it's a pharmacy !
我现在很紧张！能不能别打断我的话？
I'm applying psychological pressure ! Why are you breaking my balls ?
- 因为你话太多了   - 我干我必须做的事。快走！
- Because you're too much.   - I do what I have to do. Move !
带我们去药品库。我们要所有含丁香酚的东西
Take us to the drugs store. We want everything that contains eugenol.
香波、沐浴液等等！
Shampoo, bath foam, everything !
你看什么？聋了吗？带我们去库房！
What are you looking at ? Are you deaf ? Take us to the store !
兹尼教授！4个月前我还接受您的计算化学考试来着。。。
Professor Zinni ! I sat computational chemistry with you four months ago...
我觉得好奇怪哦，看见你们拿着刺刀站在那儿！
I thought it was strange, standing there with bayonets !
这算不算是一个人在压力下会有什么反应的测试？
Is this a test to see how people react under stress ?
- 搞什么鬼？   - 安德里亚说过要是出了什么岔子，我们就开枪
- What the fuck ?   - If things go wrong, we shoot.
- 他认出你来了！   - 我什么都没对你说过！
- He recognized you !   - I didn't say anything to you !
我们就这样杀了人？
We're shooting people now ?
你们疯了吗？你们在干什么？
Are you mad ? What are you doing ?
你本该望风的，看有没有人过来
You're supposed to be the lookout, see if anyone's coming.
当然是有人来了！现在就像列宁格勒包围战！
Of course someone's coming ! It's like the Siege of Leningrad, this is !
把你的脸遮起来，有摄像头！
Cover your face, there are cameras !
我去把卡车开来。动作快点！我在外面等着
I'm going for the truck. Hurry up ! I'll be waiting outside.
现在我们把需要的东西带走
Now we'll take what we need and leave.
我们拿什么呢？库房门有密码锁
What are we taking ? The storeroom has a combination lock.
你觉得他会输入密码？
You think he can punch in numbers ?
他在装呢！我瞧过了。药店的人一向如此！
He's acting ! I just grazed him. Pharmacists always act like that !
哦，老天，他状况不太好！
Oh, God, he's in a bad way !
我不能望了，我要吐了。能不能给我点止吐药？
I can't watch, I'll throw up. Can you get me an antiemetic ?
- 他认识你，我们得把他杀了   - 马蒂亚，搞什么？
- He knows you, we have to kill him.   - Mattia, what the fuck ?
我没想开枪，只是一时紧张走火了
I didn't mean to shoot, it went off with the nerves.
- 紧张？   - 总之，他认出你了
- The nerves ?   - Anyway, he recognized you.
- 我们都会被抓起来的   - 那么你是想打死他喽？
- We'll all be arrested.   - So you want to shoot him ?
还能怎么办？消除他的记忆？嗯？
What else ? Erase his memory ? Eh ?
我们给他包扎一下送进卡车，好吗？
Let's get some bandages and put him in the truck, all right ?
冷静！这种情况可以从积极的角度去看
Calm down ! The situation can be viewed from a positive point of view.
1、他还没死 2、交易完成 3、我没结婚
1, the guy's not dead. 2, the deal's off. 3, I'm not getting married.
不，交易还在进行。而你明天要去结婚
No, the deal's still on. And you're getting married tomorrow.
我们手上啥都没有的话拿什么交差？
What pills do we give them if we don't have any ?
我们不用丁香酚了
We make them without eugenol.
搞成这样子你却说我们可以不用丁香酚？
After all this we can make them without eugenol ?
- 不全是   - 那么？
- Not really.   - And ?
- 我还在想   - 他还在想
- I'm thinking about it.   - He's thinking about it.
彼得罗，说真的，我觉得我们没有时间思考了！
Pietro, to be frank, I don't think there's any time for thinking !
你必须告诉我们你在做什么
You have to tell us what you're doing.
这是羟丁酸钠和维柯丁，一种用于嗜睡症，另一种是镇静剂
This is Xyrem and Vicodin, one's for narcolepsy, the other's an opiate,
- 伽玛羟丁酸   - 是什么东西？
- gamma-hydroxybutyric acid.   - What's that ?
是一种作用于短期记忆的短链脂肪酸
It's a short-chain fatty acid that works on the short-term memory.
我们已经搞砸了！我们本该杀了他
We've screwed up ! We should have killed him.
马蒂亚，让他全喝光
Mattia, make him drink it all.
- 你想消除他的记忆？   - 我正在做尝试
- You want to erase his memory ?   - I'm trying to.
- 要是不行呢？   - 要是我没弄准剂量
- If you can't ?   - If I get the doses wrong,
他会从睡眠状态变成昏迷状态直到死亡！
He'll go from sleeping to being comatose to dying !
闭嘴！安静一会！抱歉，彼得罗！
Shut up! Shut up a minute! Excuse me, Pietro !
你是说真的你能让人失去记忆？
Are you really saying you can make people lose their memories ?
你没意识到你在说什么吗？消除人的记忆！
Do you realize what you're saying ? Erase people's memories !
先生们，这是生死攸关的大事！
Gentlemen, this is an important matter of life and death !
- 怎么说？   - 在奥古斯丁罗马王朝之前，僧侣怎么进行占卜？
- Yes ?    - What did the haruspices do in pre-Augustinian Rome ?
面对凶兆，僧侣会要求终止行动
Faced with a bad omen, the haruspex said to abandon the operation.
- 我们不会终止行动的   - 但是历史很少说谎！
- We're not abandoning anything.   - But history rarely lies !
我才不管！我们说的是做最后一单，而现在我们做的就是
I don't care ! We said we're doing a last deal and we're doing it.
我们手里没有药丸的话，拿什么给穆雷纳？
What will we give Murena if we've no pills ?
我钱包里还有一个。给！
They're not finished, I've got one in my wallet. Here !
- 零号。我知道   - 各位，相信我
The number zero. I know. Guys, trust me.
- 你现在给谁打电话呢？   - 我曾经授过课的家伙
- Who are you calling now ?   - A guy I give lessons to.
我们现在受制于一群毛孩子！
Now we're in the hands of some adolescent !
毛里齐奥，我是兹尼教授。没事，一切正常
Maurizio, it's Professor Zinni. No, everything's fine.
只是有件事。你父亲那家餐饮公司还开着吗？
Just one thing. Does your father still have that catering company ?
为什么我是七人中唯一一个要做出自我牺牲的？
Why am I the only one out of seven people who has to sacrifice himself ?
又不是领证。只是民间仪式罢了。就像嘉年华
It's not registered. It's folklore. It's like Carnival.
- 他们来了。我们开始   - 我是认真的
- They're here. Let's start.   - I mean it.
再怎么说，这套西装不错！
This suit is cool, though !
彼得罗，这么紧张的局面让我心动过速
Pietro, all this tension is causing me a bit of tachycardia.
当我年轻的时候，我的心脏被诊断出有个小洞
When I was young, I was diagnosed with a little hole in my heart.
因此我不得不终止了体育运动
That's why I had to stop doing sports.
- 我明白   - 我本来有个美好的前途
- I understand.   - I had a promising career.
阿图罗，别担心，不会有事的
Arturo, don't worry, nothing will happen.
那些人手里可是真家伙。要是他们开枪怎么办？
These guys have got real guns. What if they shoot ?
辛蒂式婚礼本身就很危险，没人会冲我们开枪的
A Sinti wedding is very dangerous in itself, nobody will shoot at us.
看，穆雷纳把他的合伙人带来了
Look, Murena has brought his partner.
合伙人，典型的皮条客的女人，一个妓女
Partner, the classic pimp's woman, a hooker,
站街的，娼妇，不要脸的鸡，荡妇，臭婊子。。。
peripatetic, a whore, a slapper clearly, a slut, a big tart...
看她那张脸，好像在哪见过的样子
Look at her. She's been round the block.
这不是马戏，这是魔术
This is no circus, this is for conjurors.
- 阿图罗，知道了，马上闭嘴！   - 好吧，我知道了，不说了
- Now you see it, now you don't !   - OK, I get it, stop it.
你看，她和你女朋友长得挺像的，别介意
You know, she's not unlike your girlfriend, no offence.
阿图罗，她就是我女朋友！
Arturo, she is my girlfriend !
接下来，籍由赋予我的权力，我宣布你们成为夫妻
And so, by the powers conferred on me, I declare you man and wife.
请等一下。在庆祝之前有一个小小的仪式
Just one moment. There's one small formality before the celebrations,
在这里签下字，我们就结束了
one signature here and that's us finished.
- 这只是个仪式，对不对？   - 什么意思？
- It's all folklore, isn't it ?   - In what sense ?
- 我是说，我要是签了字。。。   - 就算在市政厅注册结婚了
- I mean, I'm just signing...   - It's for the town hall.
你什么意思，市政厅？
What do you mean, for the town hall ?
- 10公斤。要是你想称一下的话   - 没必要。我相信你
- 10 kilos. If you want to weigh it.   - No need. I trust you.
不过我得试用一下。给我弄点喝的来，你们俩！
But I need to try them. get me something to drink, both of you !
彼得罗，我必须得告诉你，你弄的这玩意真不错
Pietro, I have to tell you, this stuff of yours is really good.
以前我并不认为你可以领导他们
I couldn't tell you before for leadership reasons.
以及你们工作的方式，不过你确实组织了一个很专业的团队
The way you guys work as well, you've got a professional group.
通常我不得不靠手下这些尼安德特人维持生意。。。
I always had to kind of get by with these Neanderthals I've got...
。。。但有一次也不是那样，像我们这样的人不多
...but one time it wasn't like that, there weren't many like us.
- 像我们？   - 像我们。人家为什么叫我穆雷纳？
- Like us ?   - Like us. Why am I Murena ?
因为你是个坏蛋，用了一个和鳝鱼一样的名字？
Because you're a bad guy, like the eel of the same name ?
不，穆雷纳，就像二战时的意大利皇家海军的海神级潜艇
No, Murena, like the old World War II Triton-class submarine.
他是个海军工程师，白痴！
He's a naval engineer, dickhead !
这是家族传统，我祖父设计了龙骨
It's a family tradition, my grandfather designed the keel.
我擅长流体动力，之后我被踢出了大学校门
I specialized in fluid dynamics, then I got kicked out of university.
把那个给我
Give me that.
干杯
Cheers.
挺不错，放到车里去吧
It's good, put it in the car,
拿去。照顾好你们自己，我会随时跟你们联系。再见，小姑娘
Here. Look after yourself, I'll be in touch. Bye, kid.
你告诉过我要多积累点经验，我不再想当个乖宝宝了
You told me to get some experience, I was too much of a good kid.
我确实把建议听进去了！
Talk about slavishly following advice !
信使报的社会新闻第一页！书呆子帮派
Page 1 of the city news in II Messaggero ! The Nerd Gang.
接下来是共和报，我觉得有点摩尼教的味道
Then La Repubblica which I think was a bit Manichean,
他们把我们描述成一个研究生吸毒者的帮派，太扯了
they made us out to be a gang of graduate junkies which isn't true,
因为我们都有博士学位，而且只有一个人吸毒
because we've all got doctorates and only one of us was using,
同时他们还谈到了保镖的情况
and then it was a bit suggestive with the escorts angle.
重中之重的是，一篇大作，来自我读报，你能看到
Last but not least, the masterpiece, Leggo, which you'll have seen,
带有法布隆尼的社论，一个评论作家。我来念一下
with an editorial by Fabbroni, a writer of some note. I'll read it.
- 不，等等   - 我来念一下
- No, wait.   - I'll read it.
你在那夸夸其谈，让我头很痛。这故事编得漏洞百出
When you talk, I get a headache. This story is full of holes.
这桩交易中的100万去哪了？
This million from the deal, where did it go ?
哪也没去。根本就没有那100万。彼得罗把我们骗了
To nobody. There was no million. Pietro cheated us,
真正的交易是用10公斤药丸交换朱莉亚
the deal was ten kilos of pills in exchange for Giulia.
- 但那些药丸是假的啊？   - 它们是用糖做的
- But the pills were fake ?   - They were made of sugar.
是治疗精神病用的香槟，这要谢谢零号药丸
It was the champagne that was psychotropic thanks to the zero pill.
- 毛里齐奥，听我说   - 说吧，我现在很激动！
- Maurizio, listen to me.   - Tell me, I'm all fired up!
听我说！在一个特定的时间，他们会要你提供一杯饮料
Listen to me ! At a certain point, they'll ask you for a drink.
我们就只有这个，你必须把它放进饮料里。非常重要！
This is all we have, you have to put it in the drink. It's important !
我早就知道你是个中强手！
I knew you were a real hot shot !
毛里齐奥！他们是真正的坏蛋，他们会开枪的！
Maurizio ! These are real bad guys, they'll shoot us !
酷！
Cool !
不，不，这杯不能拿！
No, no, not that one !
很不错。放进车里吧
It's good. Put it in the car.
那个药剂师呢？
And the pharmacist ?
彼得罗需要他把阿尔贝托弄出来。我们不能把他一个人留在监狱里
Pietro needed him to get Alberto out. We couldn't leave him in jail.
- 闭嘴！   - 听我说，安静！听我说，听我说，听我说！
Shut up ! Listen to me, quiet ! Listen to me, listen to me, listen to me !
去找彼得罗，他们对帮派的事了如指掌，精神药剂，穆雷纳！
Go to Pietro, they know everything about the gang, smart drugs, Murena !
- 我们全都会被抓起来的！明白吗？   - 不懂   - 还不明白？
They'll arrest us all ! Understand ? Niet ?
这么说你打算去投案？
So you're handing yourself in ?
不，我去申请认罪宽恕。我来对我们做的一切负全责
No, I'm plea bargaining. I accept responsibility for all we did,
- 但你得放了其他人一马   - 我凭什么这么做呢？
- but you have to let the others be.   - And why would I do that ?
因为我会把穆雷纳交给你们。你们要做的就是在公路尽头放个路障
Because I'll give you Murena. All you need is a road block on the Casilino.
在卡车里，你们能找到足够判他10年的东西
In the trunk, you'll find enough to put him away for ten years.
计划是在穆雷纳带着10公斤药的时候抓到他
The plans was to let Murena get caught with 10 kilos.
- 但是你说那些是假药   - 其实，还有B计划
- But you said they were false.   - In fact, there was a plan B.
正因为如此，我们必须得找到一个能让穆雷纳被捕的方法
Because of that, we had to find a way to get Murena arrested,
而绑架是最好的方法。那个药剂师什么都不会记得
and kidnap was the best way. The pharmacist wouldn't remember a thing.
其他人呢？
What happened to the others ?
这是150平米的休息厅，是真正的珠宝
This is lounge which with its 150 square meters is a jewel,
在这你能拥有极佳的罗马市区视角！这就是那个露台
which as you can see has a splendid view of Rome ! This is the terrace.
乔吉奥和马蒂亚欠了那家宾馆4万欧元
Giorgio and Mattia owed 40,000 euros to the hotel
而且只有一种办法去偿还
and had only one way to pay.
对，它是有点挡事，不过那恐怕是承重柱，动不了
Yes, it's a bit claustrophobic, but this is a bearing pillar, I'm afraid.
巴尔托洛梅奥。。。这桩婚姻应该是有效的
Bartolomeo... The marriage turned out to be valid.
主持婚礼的官员是真的，所以我们可以说他已经合法结婚了
The council official was real, so let's say he's sorted.
要是打算出售一头骆驼，你必须怎么做？
If someone wanted to sell a camel, what to do you have to do ?
- 你又不是卖骆驼的   - 咱们走着瞧
- You don't sell the camel.   - We'll see about that.
阿尔贝托正在康复之中。据说情况良好
Alberto is in recovery. They say he's making progress.
我说的可不是经营一、两个街区的事，不是，不是
I'm not talking about running one or two neighborhoods, no, no !
不，我曾经是罗马之王！脚踏整个罗马，你明白吗？
No, I was the King of Rome ! Rome was at my feet, you understand ?
不，我是说真的！你笑什么？
No, really! Why are you laughing ?
各位，静一静！我们知道某些东西会导致困惑。。。
Guys, please ! We know certain substances cause confusion...
困惑，神父？你在质疑我几个月的犯罪行为吗？
Confusion, Father ? You're doubting my months of criminal activity ?
我有质疑你的神圣道路吗？拜托！。。。抱歉
Do I challenge your spiritual path ? Excuse me ! Excuse me.
- 事情办得怎样？   - 不错
- How did it go ?   - Great.
他真是个可爱的家伙
He's a really lovely person.
我把事情全都跟他说了，他很感兴趣。。。
I told him the whole story, he listened with great interest...
- 于是他决定用你了？   - 我跟他达成了君子协定
- So he took you on ?   - I made a gentleman's agreement,
跟他之间合作胜过其它合同千百倍
which with someone like him is worth a thousand contracts.
我得到了12到18个月的无薪实习期，然后看情况了
I've got a 12-18 month unpaid apprenticeship, then we'll see.
- 无薪   - 对
- Unpaid.   - Yes.
我想会从周一开始。对，按理说，我不能带着这狗
I think I start Monday. Yes, in the sense, I can't keep the dog.
我不能带着它去工作。我已经承担了被开除的风险
I can't take it on site. I've already risked being fired,
- 我已经旷了不少天的工   - 我们一起来处理吧
- all those days off.   - We'll deal with this together,
开个会，并且说明这是集体的责任
have a meeting and point out it's a collective responsibility,
我觉得我们最好是轮流来。。。
I think we need some kind of turntable system...
所以现在要让元素平衡，我们得添加。。。？添加。。。
So now we balance the element with the addition of...? The addition...
电子。各位，氧化还原反应，是这个公式第四步的关键
Electrons. Guys, redox is at the heart of the 4th-year program.
你们觉得怎样才能获得学位？
How do you think you'll get your diploma ?
你们中一部分人需要用它获得保释。。。我就不点名字了
Some of you need it to get parole... no names, eh, Amed ?
你们走吧，救命的下课铃响了！探视时间到！你们得去工作了
On you go, saved by the bell ! Visiting time ! You need to work.
斯巴达克，你起步很好，接着就停止不前了！怎么努力的，嗯！
Spartaco, you started off well and then drew up ! What a struggle, eh !
不过还不算坏。这个公式很难，我们到了氧化还原阶段
But it's not bad. The program is hard, we're at redox,
我教的这些都是北非人，他们天生就会数学
I've got all these North Africans, they've got numbers in their blood.
是不是啊？
Isn't that right ?
彼得罗，你可能6个月内就能出去了，通过缓刑
Pietro, you might get out in six months, get probation.
- 谁说的？   - 维托利奥告诉我的
- Says who ?   - Vittorio told me.
他知道些什么？他是个教会律师。和刑事案完全不沾边
What does he know ? He's a canon lawyer. Penal's totally different.
对，但是我们需要你的教师工资。同样为了孩子
Yes, but we need your teacher's salary here. For the boy as well.
宝贝，别担心，总会有办法的
Baby, don't worry, there's always an answer.
我头上这把达摩克利斯之剑正展现好的一面！
I've got this sword of Damocles of good behavior hanging over me !
我们就不能策划一下？
Can't we arrange something ?
我已经和阿尔巴尼亚人计划好了餐厅的骚乱
I've organized a riot in the canteen with the Albanians.
要是有人被捅伤了，我可能再得到一年减刑。了不起吧！
If someone gets stabbed, I might get another year. That's something !
不是吗？
No?
玩命毒师
I CAN QUIT ANYTIME I WANT